PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Rho, EHR; Haimson, OL; Andalibi, N; Mazmanian, M; Hayes, GR			ACM	Rho, Eugenia Ha Rim; Haimson, Oliver L.; Andalibi, Nazanin; Mazmanian, Melissa; Hayes, Gillian R.			Class Confessions: Restorative Properties in Online Experiences of Socioeconomic Stigma	PROCEEDINGS OF THE 2017 ACM SIGCHI CONFERENCE ON HUMAN FACTORS IN COMPUTING SYSTEMS (CHI'17)					ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI)	MAY 06-11, 2017	Denver, CO	Assoc Comp Machinery, ACM SIGCHI				In this paper, we examine stigma related to class identity online through an empirical examination of Elite University Class Confessions (EUCC). EUCC is an online space that includes a Facebook page and a surrounding sociotechnical ecosystem. It is a community of, for, and about low-income and first generation students at an elite university. By bringing in a community that learns and engages with users' socioeconomic struggles, EUCC engenders unique restorative properties for students experiencing class stigma. EUCC's restorative properties foster new ways of understanding one's stigmatized identity through meaning-making interactions in a networked sociotechnical system. We discuss how EUCC's design shapes the nature of user interactions around class stigma, and explore in depth how people experience stigma differently through the restorative properties of EUCC.																			978-1-4503-4655-9				2017							3377	3389		10.1145/3025453.3025921								WOS:000426970503027						
