PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Patel, R; Chaudhari, T			IEEE	Patel, Roshani; Chaudhari, Tarunika			A Review on Sequential Pattern Mining using Pattern Growth Approach	PROCEEDINGS OF THE 2016 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS, SIGNAL PROCESSING AND NETWORKING (WISPNET)					IEEE International Conference on Wireless Communications, Signal Processing and Networking (WiSPNET)	MAR 23-25, 2016	Dept Elect & Commun Engn, Chennai, INDIA	IEEE, SSN Inst, IEEE Madras Sect, ISRO, DRDO, Cognizant, mGage, APCER, ELMAC, Global Acad Conf Platform	Dept Elect & Commun Engn			One of the important approach in data mining is sequential pattern mining that is used for discovering behaviors of sequential databases. There are various challenges in sequential pattern mining such as efficiency and effectiveness. In this paper different sequential pattern mining algorithm are discussed such as GSP, FreeSpan, PrefixSpan, and CAI-PrefixSpan to improve performance to finding sequential pattern. Many constraint have been proposed to obtain useful pattern like time interval between item, gap between two purchased item etc. Existing CAI-PrefixSpan algorithm was implementing with time constraint which give time from when customer purchase item first time. The comparative analysis show the performance of algorithm based on parameter.																			978-1-4673-9337-9				2016							1424	1427										WOS:000388601800292						
