PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Sangeetha, V; Kumar, SS			IEEE	Sangeetha, V; Kumar, S. Swapna			ZIDS: Zonal-based Intrusion Detection System for Studying the Malicious Node Behaviour in MANET	2015 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON EMERGING RESEARCH IN ELECTRONICS, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (ICERECT)					International Conference on Emerging Research in Electronics, Computer Science and Technology (ICERECT)	DEC 17-19, 2015	Mandya, INDIA					The communication behaviour of mobile nodes in adhoc network are quite confusing to understand owing to the decentralized architecture and dynamic topology. The existing system has presented various security solutions in order to understand the malicious activity of the adversary. Therefore, designing a model to strengthen up the intrusion detection system based on the uncertain and unpredictable malicious behaviour of the adversary is computationally challenging problem. This paper presents a technique called as ZIDS i. e. Zonal-based Intrusion Detection System that uses potential of game theory in order to extracts the uncertain strategies of the malicious node. ZIDS offers an extensive security against multiple and discrete attacker. Compared with the recent studies, ZIDS excels best with respect to accuracy in detection rate and processing time for ensuring accurate detection of malicious nodes and events.																			978-1-4673-9563-2				2015							276	281										WOS:000411710100050						
