PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Sophia, KTE; Kanchi, RR			IEEE	Sophia, Eunice K. T.; Kanchi, Raghavendra Rao			Wind Speed and Direction Measurement System Using Atmel 89S51 Microcontroller	2016 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INVENTIVE COMPUTATION TECHNOLOGIES (ICICT), VOL 3					IEEE International Conference on Inventive Computation Technologies (ICICT)	AUG 26-27, 2016	Coimbatore, INDIA	IEEE, IEEE Electron Devices Soc, RVS Tech Campus, Invent Res Org				This paper presents a simple instrumentation design built around one of the 8051 family microcontroller to measure instantaneous wind speed and wind direction. This system includes an improved, yet an inexpensive cup anemometer: Davis Instruments 6410 to sense the above said two wind parameters. The accuracy of the processing system is estimated prior to the interfacing the system with the wind sensor. The software is developed in C language and the data is displayed on 16x2 LCD for every three seconds. The collected data is then plotted in circular histogram for analysis. The system designed has the potential to be further developed and be used for in applications for the reason of its effective measurement which correlated well with the standard readings.																							2015							464	469										WOS:000414242300094						
