PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Gunasekaran, V; Banerjee, J; Dwivedi, SN; Upadhyay, AD; Chatterjee, P; Dey, AB				Gunasekaran, Venugopalan; Banerjee, Joyita; Dwivedi, Sada Nand; Upadhyay, Ashish Datt; Chatterjee, Prashun; Dey, Aparajit Ballav			Normal gait speed, grip strength and thirty seconds chair stand test among older Indians	ARCHIVES OF GERONTOLOGY AND GERIATRICS												Introduction: Gait speed, maximum grip strength and thirty seconds chair stand test are quick, reliable measures of functional capacity in older adults. The objective of this study was to develop normative data of the said parameters, which is lacking in older Indians. Methodology: In a cross sectional study, 723 participants of >= 60 years without any morbidity, were recruited with written consent at Geriatric Medicine clinic of All India Institute of Medical sciences, New Delhi. Time taken to walk comfortably (4 m) was taken as Gait speed. Maximum grip strength was assessed by using dynamometer by pressing it for 3 times in each hand, and the best of six values noted. Thirty second chair stand was assessed by the number of repetitions to stand and sit from a chair in thirty second. Result: The Cut-off (25th percentile) of gait speed for both male and female in all age group was 0.6 m/s. The Cut-off for maximum grip strength in 60-65 years, 66-70 years and >70 years for male were 20, 15 and 15 and for females were 8, 6 and 6 in kg, respectively. The Cut-off for thirty second chair stand test in 60-65 years, 66-70 years and >70 years for male were 10, 9 and 8 and for females was 8, 8 and 7, respectively. Conclusion: These normative data would be useful to the clinicians and researcher as Indian reference value, which is less as compared to western data. Community based multi-centre study is needed. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ireland Ltd. All rights reserved.																	0167-4943	1872-6976				NOV-DEC	2016	67						171	178		10.1016/j.archger.2016.08.003								WOS:000382269200025	27552583					
