PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Arora, B; Choudhury, T; Kumar, P; Mukherjee		Agrawal, A; Verma, M; Prakash, GL; Alind; Saini, R; Bisht, S; Chaudhary, S		Arora, Bhawna; Choudhury, Tanupriya; Kumar, Praveen; Mukherjee			An Intelligent Way to Play Music By Brain Activity Using Brain Computer Interface	PROCEEDINGS ON 2016 2ND INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON NEXT GENERATION COMPUTING TECHNOLOGIES (NGCT)					2nd IEEE International Conference on Next Generation Computing Technologies (NGCT)	OCT 14-16, 2016	UnivPetr & Energy Studies, Dehradun, INDIA	IEEE, IEEE UP Sect, DRDO, DST, RCPL, Sci & Engn Res Board, Govt India, Dept Sci & Technol, UnivPetr & Energy Studies, Ctr Informat Technol	UnivPetr & Energy Studies			This research focuses on advent of music player that could be controlled by the human brain by BCI using EEG (electroencephalogram). The rudimentary idea is user contemplates to change the song and eases while listening. The indorsed BCI system implements deciphering the brain state by use of (EEG) signals, in amalgamation with M.L, A. I. These days research is fundamentally being concentrated on developing BCI system applications. In this paper ephemeral explanation of how music system would play using brain activity and what mechanism is involved has been enlightened along with an proposed algorithm by the use of wavelets and emphasis has also be been laid on diverse BCI systems that have previously technologically advanced and are currently in custom.																			978-1-5090-3257-0				2016							223	228										WOS:000405575500040						
