PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Blain, GC; Pires, RCD				Blain, Gabriel Constantino; de Matos Pires, Regina Clelia			Temporal variability of the actual evapotranspiration and the ratio between actual and potential evapotranspiration in Campinas, State of Sao Paulo, Brazil	BRAGANTIA												The aim of the work was to characterize the temporal variability of ten-day evapotranspiration series, considering the actual evapotranspiration (ETa) and the ratio between actual and potential evapotranspiration (ETa/ETP). Data between 1948 and 2008 were collected with a weather station in Campinas, State of Sao Paulo, Brazil. Evapotranspiration calculation considered three values of soil water availability (SWA): 50, 100, and 150 mm. Based on autocorrelation function, it was detected a significant level of temporal persistence on ETa and ETa/ETP series. The acf also has indicated that this temporal persistence tends to increase due to high SWA values. The spectral analysis has shown a decreasing power of these series after 1976. The El Nino/southern oscillation influence on ETa and ETa/ETP temporal variability was not conclusive. The Seasonal Mann-Kendall test has shown increasing trends on ETa series in the months of January, May, July, September, November and December. The ETa/ETP series was little affected by the increasing trends detected on ETP series.				Blain, Gabriel/I-2501-2012	Blain, Gabriel/0000-0001-8832-7734												1678-4499					APR-JUN	2011	70	2					460	470		10.1590/S0006-87052011000200030								WOS:000294394300031						
