PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Denfeld, BA; Kortelainen, P; Rantakari, M; Sobek, S; Weyhenmeyer, GA				Denfeld, Blaize A.; Kortelainen, Pirkko; Rantakari, Miitta; Sobek, Sebastian; Weyhenmeyer, Gesa A.			Regional Variability and Drivers of Below Ice CO2 in Boreal and Subarctic Lakes	ECOSYSTEMS			English	Article						CO2; winter limnology; ice cover; carbon; nutrients; lake depth	DISSOLVED ORGANIC-MATTER; GREENHOUSE-GAS EMISSIONS; CARBON-DIOXIDE; SURFACE WATERS; INLAND WATERS; METHANE; RESPIRATION; METABOLISM; CLIMATE; STREAMS	Northern lakes are ice-covered for considerable portions of the year, where carbon dioxide (CO2) can accumulate below ice, subsequently leading to high CO2 emissions at ice-melt. Current knowledge on the regional control and variability of below ice partial pressure of carbon dioxide (pCO(2)) is lacking, creating a gap in our understanding of how ice cover dynamics affect the CO2 accumulation below ice and therefore CO2 emissions from inland waters during the ice-melt period. To narrow this gap, we identified the drivers of below ice pCO(2) variation across 506 Swedish and Finnish lakes using water chemistry, lake morphometry, catchment characteristics, lake position, and climate variables. We found that lake depth and trophic status were the most important variables explaining variations in below ice pCO(2) across the 506 lakes(.) Together, lake morphometry and water chemistry explained 53% of the site-to-site variation in below ice pCO(2). Regional climate (including ice cover duration) and latitude only explained 7% of the variation in below ice pCO(2). Thus, our results suggest that on a regional scale a shortening of the ice cover period on lakes may not directly affect the accumulation of CO2 below ice but rather indirectly through increased mobility of nutrients and carbon loading to lakes. Thus, given that climate-induced changes are most evident in northern ecosystems, adequately predicting the consequences of a changing climate on future CO2 emission estimates from northern lakes involves monitoring changes not only to ice cover but also to changes in the trophic status of lakes.	[Denfeld, Blaize A.; Sobek, Sebastian; Weyhenmeyer, Gesa A.] Uppsala Univ, Dept Ecol & Genet Limnol, Evolutionary Biol Ctr, Norbyvagen 18D, S-75236 Uppsala, Sweden; [Kortelainen, Pirkko] Finnish Environm Inst, POB 140, Helsinki 00251, Finland; [Rantakari, Miitta] Univ Helsinki, Dept Environm Sci, Viikinkaari 9, FIN-00014 Helsinki, Finland; [Rantakari, Miitta] Univ Helsinki, Dept Phys, Gustaf Hallstromin Katu 2a, Helsinki 00560, Finland	Denfeld, BA (reprint author), Uppsala Univ, Dept Ecol & Genet Limnol, Evolutionary Biol Ctr, Norbyvagen 18D, S-75236 Uppsala, Sweden.	Blaize.Denfeld@ebc.uu.se		Rantakari, Miitta Maria/0000-0003-2335-6192	NordForsk; Swedish Research Council (VR); Swedish Research Council for Environment, Agricultural Sciences and Spatial Planning (FORMAS); NordForsk (DOMQUA); Norwegian Research Council (Norklima ECCO); US National Science Foundation (GLEON); European Union (Netlake)	The financial support was received from the NordForsk approved Nordic Centre of Excellence "CRAICC," the Swedish Research Council (VR), and the Swedish Research Council for Environment, Agricultural Sciences and Spatial Planning (FORMAS). This work is part of and profited from the networks financed by NordForsk (DOMQUA), Norwegian Research Council (Norklima ECCO), US National Science Foundation (GLEON), and the European Union (Netlake). We would like to thank Roger Muller for valuable discussions on GIS data and statistical methods. We would also like to thank two anonymous reviewers for useful comments that have improved the manuscript.		64	3	3	1	25	SPRINGER	NEW YORK	233 SPRING ST, NEW YORK, NY 10013 USA	1432-9840	1435-0629		ECOSYSTEMS	Ecosystems	APR	2016	19	3					461	476		10.1007/s10021-015-9944-z				16	Ecology	Environmental Sciences & Ecology	DH8BL	WOS:000373018200007		gold_or_bronze			2018-09-28	
