PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Semakula, I; Samsuri, S			IEEE	Semakula, Isa; Samsuri, Suhaila			Green Computing Knowledge among Students in a Ugandan University	2016 6TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY FOR THE MUSLIM WORLD (ICT4M)	International Conference on Information and Communication Technology for the Muslim World		English	Proceedings Paper	6th International Conference on Information and Communication Technology for The Muslim World (ICT4M)	NOV 22-24, 2016	Syarif Hidayatullah State Islamic Univ, Jakarta, INDONESIA	ENSIAS, JAKIM, Perpustakaan Negara Malaysia	Syarif Hidayatullah State Islamic Univ	Green computing; Green IT; Computer experience; Carbon footprint; e-waste; IUIU		Humans, including students, are partly responsible for rising levels of global warming through unsustainable computing practices. It is imperative that students participate in the global drive to reduce global warming through activities like green computing which advocates for sustainable use of computing resources to reduce energy consumption and carbon emissions. The study was conducted to establish green computing awareness levels of students from Islamic University in Uganda (IUIU) and also determine if such levels were influenced by computer experience. Results from a purposive sample of 452 students indicated that students' levels of green computing awareness were low, and computer experience influenced two of the three dimensions of perceived knowledge of green computing.	[Semakula, Isa; Samsuri, Suhaila] Int Islamic Univ Malaysia, Kulliyyah Informat & Commun Technol, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia	Semakula, I (reprint author), Int Islamic Univ Malaysia, Kulliyyah Informat & Commun Technol, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.	issemak@gmail.com; suhailasamsuri@iium.edu.my						25	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2376-4074		978-1-5090-4521-1	INT CONF INFORM COMM			2016							199	204		10.1109/ICT4M.2016.44				6	Computer Science, Interdisciplinary Applications; Telecommunications	Computer Science; Telecommunications	BG9IX	WOS:000393294000036					2018-09-30	
