PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Shuaib, MM				Shuaib, Mohammed Mahmod			Incorporating intelligence for typical evacuation under the threat of fire spreading	SAFETY SCIENCE			English	Article						Evacuation; Fire spreading; Decision-making; Exit-choice; Precaution time	SOCIAL FORCE MODEL; PEDESTRIAN EVACUATION; CELLULAR-AUTOMATON; EMERGENCY EVACUATION; HUMAN-BEHAVIOR; TUNNEL FIRE; EXIT CHOICE; SIMULATION; DYNAMICS; OPTIMIZATION	Having to escape from a moving threat, such as a fire, is a tremendously frightening event during an evacuation. Evacuees' decisions in such circumstances could be better made with an awareness of fire dynamics and potential risks. Rationality is a human factor which has an essential role in accomplishing typical evacuation in emergency situations. In this article, the authors propose a rule-based exit choice model in which the simulated individuals are provided with the assessment of exit's disutility and decision-making capability for selecting and reselecting exits due to the evacuation dynamics. The model allows for the simulation of systematic crowd distribution at exits up until the end of the evacuation process, thereby accomplishing a more efficient evacuation. For further refinement, we allow the individuals to predict the dynamics of the fire spreading and involve its effect on the individuals' assessment. We consider a precaution time for each individual as an essential parameter to guarantee safety from the fire spreading or equivalent risk. Simulations are performed and the discussion of fast and safe decision-making are introduced.	[Shuaib, Mohammed Mahmod] Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic Univ, Dept Comp & Informat Sci, Coll Sharia & Islamic Studies, Alahsaa 31982, Saudi Arabia	Shuaib, MM (reprint author), Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic Univ, Dept Comp & Informat Sci, Coll Sharia & Islamic Studies, Alahsaa 31982, Saudi Arabia.	mmshoaab@imamu.edu.sa			Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University	We thank the Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University for supporting this work.		89	0	0	21	21	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0925-7535	1879-1042		SAFETY SCI	Saf. Sci.	JUL	2018	106						1	9		10.1016/j.ssci.2018.02.022				9	Engineering, Industrial; Operations Research & Management Science	Engineering; Operations Research & Management Science	GH2YJ	WOS:000433267600001					2018-09-30	
