PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Shuaib, M; Zainuddin, Z				Shuaib, Mohammed; Zainuddin, Zarita			Incorporating Intelligence into Exit Choice Model for Typical Evacuation	SAINS MALAYSIANA			English	Article						Decision making; evacuation; exit choice; prediction	SOCIAL FORCE MODEL; PEDESTRIAN DYNAMICS; EFFICIENCY; EMERGENCY	Integrating an exit choice model into a microscopic crowd dynamics model is an essential approach for obtaining more efficient evacuation model. We describe various aspects of decision-making capability of an existing rule-based exit choice model for evacuation processes. In simulations, however, the simulated evacuees clogging at exits have behaved non-intelligently, namely they do not give up their exits for better ones for safer egress. We refine the model to endow the individuals with the ability to leave their exits due to dynamic changes by modifying the model of their excitement resulted from the source of panic. This facilitates the approximately equal crowd size at exits for being until the end of the evacuation process, and thereby the model accomplishes more optimal evacuation. For further intelligence, we introduce the prediction factor that enables higher probability of equally distributing evacuees at exits. A simulation to validate the contribution is performed, and the results are analyzed and compared with the original model.	[Shuaib, Mohammed] Al Imam Muhammad Ibn Saud Islamic Univ IMSIU, Coll Sharia & Islamic Studies Al Ahsaa, Dept Comp Sci, Alahsaa 31982, Saudi Arabia; [Zainuddin, Zarita] Univ Sains Malaysia, Sch Math Sci, George Town 11800, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia	Shuaib, M (reprint author), Al Imam Muhammad Ibn Saud Islamic Univ IMSIU, Coll Sharia & Islamic Studies Al Ahsaa, Dept Comp Sci, Alahsaa 31982, Saudi Arabia.	mh_shuaib@yahoo.com			Al-Imam Muhammad Ibn Saud Islamic University [370807]	We thank the Al-Imam Muhammad Ibn Saud Islamic University for supporting this work under the project No. 370807.		28	0	0	1	1	UNIV KEBANGSAAN MALAYSIA	SELANGOR	FACULTY SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY, BANGI, SELANGOR, 43600, MALAYSIA	0126-6039			SAINS MALAYS	Sains Malays.	OCT	2017	46	10					1997	2005		10.17576/jsm-2017-4610-39				9	Multidisciplinary Sciences	Science & Technology - Other Topics	FS0YM	WOS:000419500400039					2018-09-30	
