PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Seitz, MJ; Dietrich, F; Koster, G				Seitz, Michael J.; Dietrich, Felix; Koester, Gerta			The effect of stepping on pedestrian trajectories	PHYSICA A-STATISTICAL MECHANICS AND ITS APPLICATIONS			English	Article						Pedestrian dynamics; Simulation; Controlled experiments; Stepping behaviour; Empirical	CELLULAR-AUTOMATON; DYNAMICS; BEHAVIOR; MODEL; SIMULATION; FLOWS; ORGANIZATION; EVACUATION; CROWDS; SPEED	The natural biomechanical motion process of many animals is stepwise. This feature of human movement and other bipeds is largely ignored in simulation models of pedestrians and crowds. We present a concise movement model for pedestrians based on stepwise movement. A series of controlled experiments was conducted to calibrate the model based on individual behaviour of pedestrians. We find that a change of direction is constrained by the current walking speed: the higher the speed the smaller the possible change of direction. Additionally, we present the trajectories and distances subjects held to a wall when walking around a corner. We use this result as a parameter for the simulation model. Finally, we validate the model's behaviour with an egress scenario with a corridor as bottleneck. The resulting trajectories show behaviour that has been found in controlled experiments with similar set-ups: if there is enough space, individuals try to walk in the middle of the corridor, but when a congestion is present multiple lanes form allowing for higher pedestrian flow. The model separates the behavioural aspects from biomechanical movement thus facilitating expandability and allowing experts to focus on their respective fields of expertise. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.	[Seitz, Michael J.; Dietrich, Felix; Koester, Gerta] Munich Univ Appl Sci, Munich, Germany; [Seitz, Michael J.; Dietrich, Felix] Tech Univ Munich, D-80290 Munich, Germany	Seitz, MJ (reprint author), Munich Univ Appl Sci, Munich, Germany.	m.seitz@hm.edu		Dietrich, Felix/0000-0002-2906-1769; Koester, Gerta/0000-0002-3369-6206	German Federal Ministry of Education and Research [13N12824]; Faculty Graduate Center CeDoSIA of TUM Graduate School at Technische Universitat Munchen, Germany; TopMath Graduate Center of TUM Graduate School at Technische Universitat Munchen, Germany; TopMath Program at the Elite Network of Bavaria	We thank Maik Boltes, Mohcine Chraibi and Daniel Salden from Forschungszentrum Julich for advice on video analysis techniques. This work was partially funded by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research through the project MultikOSi on assistance systems for urban events-multi criteria integration for openness and safety (Grant No. 13N12824). The authors gratefully acknowledge the support by the Faculty Graduate Center CeDoSIA of TUM Graduate School at Technische Universitat Munchen, Germany. Support from the TopMath Graduate Center of TUM Graduate School at Technische Universitat Munchen, Germany, and from the TopMath Program at the Elite Network of Bavaria is gratefully acknowledged.		52	9	10	0	29	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0378-4371	1873-2119		PHYSICA A	Physica A	MAR 1	2015	421						594	604		10.1016/j.physa.2014.11.064				11	Physics, Multidisciplinary	Physics	CA1RB	WOS:000348688200053					2018-09-30	
