PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Zainuddin, Z; Shuaib, MMA				Zainuddin, Z.; Shuaib, M. M. A.			Modelling the independence factor and its effect on the preferred force of the Social Force Model in emergency and non-emergency situations	APPLIED MATHEMATICS & INFORMATION SCIENCES			English	Article						Social force model; preferred force; independence factor		Representing the reality of the pedestrian route choice activity in both normal and evacuation situations has not been completely done due to some inaccuracies in representing the functionality of the independence factor that governs the preferred force. In addition, the limited options available to the pedestrians while they are in emergency situations are unrealistic. Hence, in this paper, we have introduced a brief demonstration of the factors that govern the preferred force. Then, we have modified the concept of the independence factor of pedestrians and subsequently modelled the effects of this factor on the pedestrian's decision-making while he is in motion. Lastly, we have introduced more features into the preferred force of the original Social Force Model to give the pedestrians more options and, in turn, make it appear more representative of what actually happens in reality.	[Zainuddin, Z.; Shuaib, M. M. A.] Univ Sains Malaysia, Sch Math Sci, George Town 11800, Malaysia	Zainuddin, Z (reprint author), Univ Sains Malaysia, Sch Math Sci, George Town 11800, Malaysia.	zarita@cs.usm.my; mh_shuaib@yahoo.com			Universiti Sains Malaysia	We thank the Universiti Sains Malaysia for supporting this work under the USM Fellowship. We also thank Prof. D.J. Kaup of the Institute for Simulation and Training, University of Central Florida, for the pedestrian simulator written in Matlab, which provides useful insights for the development of the simulations.		11	8	8	0	5	NATURAL SCIENCES PUBLISHING CORPORATION	KALAMAZOO	WESTERN MICHIGAN UNIV, 1903 W MICHIGAN AVE, KALAMAZOO, MI 49008-5252 USA	1935-0090			APPL MATH INFORM SCI	Appl. Math. Inf. Sci.	JAN	2011	5	1					53	64						12	Mathematics, Applied; Physics, Mathematical	Mathematics; Physics	853NW	WOS:000297434000005					2018-09-30	
