PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Zainuddin, Z; Shuaib, M				Zainuddin, Zarita; Shuaib, Mohammed			MODIFICATION OF THE DECISION-MAKING CAPABILITY IN THE SOCIAL FORCE MODEL FOR THE EVACUATION PROCESS	TRANSPORT THEORY AND STATISTICAL PHYSICS			English	Article						Independent Pedestrian; Decision Making; Exit Choice; Evacuation	PEDESTRIAN DYNAMICS; EXISTING BUILDINGS; SIMULATION; FIRE; COMPUTER; CHOICE	The Social Force Model is one of the most successful microscopic pedestrian models that represent the well-organized phenomena of the pedestrian flow. The model has been modified for evacuation process by incorporating physical forces when contact exists, on one hand, and incorporating factors into the preferred velocity to govern the individual's behavior corresponding to the situation under consideration (normal or evacuation) on the other hand. The latter incorporation has enhanced the ability of the model to represent the decision-making process of pedestrians. However, the variety of pedestrian's abilities to make decisions in emergency situations has not been incorporated properly into the model. In this article we enhance the decision-making capability of the independent pedestrians first by improving the assessment process of selecting an exit from the set of exits available in the physical environment by considering a new factor (crowd at exits); and second, by incorporating following crowds as a new feature for those who are independent. A simulation of an emergency situation inside a room is performed to validate our work.	[Zainuddin, Zarita; Shuaib, Mohammed] Univ Sains Malaysia, Sch Math Sci, Usm 11800, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia	Zainuddin, Z (reprint author), Univ Sains Malaysia, Sch Math Sci, Usm 11800, Pulau Pinang, Malaysia.	zarita@cs.usm.my			Universiti Sains Malaysia; USM-RU-PRGS; USM RU	We thank Universiti Sains Malaysia for supporting this work under the USM Fellowship, USM-RU-PRGS Grant, and USM RU Grant. We also thank Prof. D.J. Kaup of the Institute for Simulation and Training, University of Central Florida, for the pedestrian simulator written in Matlab, which provides useful insights for the development of the simulations. We also thank the editor and the reviewers for their valuable suggestions.		38	10	11	0	21	TAYLOR & FRANCIS INC	PHILADELPHIA	530 WALNUT STREET, STE 850, PHILADELPHIA, PA 19106 USA	0041-1450	1532-2424		TRANSPORT THEOR STAT	Transport. Theor. Statist. Phys.		2010	39	1					47	70		10.1080/00411450.2010.529979				24	Mathematics, Applied; Physics, Mathematical	Mathematics; Physics	731QK	WOS:000288124100002					2018-09-30	
