PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Langston, PA; Masling, R; Asmar, BN				Langston, PA; Masling, R; Asmar, BN			Crowd dynamics discrete element multi-circle model	SAFETY SCIENCE			English	Article						crowd dynamics; DEM; safety; mathematical modelling; egress	EVACUATION; SIMULATION	A Discrete Element Method (DEM) technique for modelling crowd dynamics is developed. Each person is represented by three overlapping circles with a position, orientation and velocity in 2D. Contact forces between elements are modelled as well as psychological forces and motive forces and moments. Motion is then modelled in a Newtonian manner with a numerical integration time-stepping scheme. The model is tested on a single enclosure entry scenario where some model parameters are scaled. Motion is generally realistic, although areas for improvement are identified. Flow and contact forces are monitored under different scenarios. The model is then used on a multi-enclosure entry scenario. It is shown that stewarding significantly reduces contact forces and hence risk of injury. The potential for further applications is demonstrated on hypothetical scenarios on the London Underground. It is concluded that the model is reasonably realistic for dense crowd flow scenarios, but more complex situations like a supermarket would require aspects of Artificial Intelligence in the model, which is a feasible development. The three-circle representation gives a reasonable model of the 2D geometry. (C) 2005 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.	Univ Nottingham, Sch Chem Environm & Min Engn, Nottingham NG7 2RD, England	Langston, PA (reprint author), Univ Nottingham, Sch Chem Environm & Min Engn, Nottingham NG7 2RD, England.	p.langston@nottingbam.ac.uk		Langston, Paul/0000-0001-7388-0684				18	68	72	3	18	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0925-7535			SAFETY SCI	Saf. Sci.	JUN	2006	44	5					395	417		10.1016/j.ssci.2005.11.007				23	Engineering, Industrial; Operations Research & Management Science	Engineering; Operations Research & Management Science	048JE	WOS:000237942600003					2018-09-30	
