PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Balachandran, BM; Prasad, S		ZanniMerk, C; Frydman, C; Toro, C; Hicks, Y; Howlett, RJ; Jain, LC		Balachandran, Bala M.; Prasad, Shivika			Challenges and Benefits of Deploying Big Data Analytics in the Cloud for Business Intelligence	KNOWLEDGE-BASED AND INTELLIGENT INFORMATION & ENGINEERING SYSTEMS	Procedia Computer Science		English	Proceedings Paper	21st International Conference on Knowledge - Based and Intelligent Information and Engineering Systems (KES)	SEP 06-08, 2017	Aix Marseille Univ, St Charles Campus, Marseille, FRANCE	Lab Sci Informat Syst, KES Int	Aix Marseille Univ, St Charles Campus	Cloud Computing; Big Data Analytics; Cloud Analytics; Security; Privacy; Business Intelligence; MapReduce; AaaS; CLaaS		Cloud computing and big data analytics are, without a doubt, two of the most important technologies to enter the mainstream IT industry in recent years. Surprisingly, the two technologies are coming together to deliver powerful results and benefits for businesses. Cloud computing is already changing the way IT services are provided by so called cloud companies and how businesses and users interact with IT resources. Big Data is a data analysis methodology enables by recent advances in information and communications technology. However, big data analysis requires a huge amount of computing resources making adoption costs of big data technology is not affordable for many small to medium enterprises. In this paper, we outline the the benefits and challenges involved in deploying big data analytics through cloud computing. We argue that cloud computing can support the storage and computing requirements of big data analytics. We discuss how the consolidation of these two dominant technologies can enhance the process of big data mining enabling businesses to improve decision-making processes. We also highlight the issues and risks that should be addressed when using a so called CLaaS, cloud-based service model. (C) 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.	[Balachandran, Bala M.; Prasad, Shivika] Univ South Pacific, Sch Comp Informat & Math Sci, Fac FSTE, Laucala Campus, Suva, Fiji	Balachandran, BM (reprint author), Univ South Pacific, Sch Comp Informat & Math Sci, Fac FSTE, Laucala Campus, Suva, Fiji.	balachandran_b@usp.ac.fj						21	0	0	6	6	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	SARA BURGERHARTSTRAAT 25, PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	1877-0509			PROCEDIA COMPUT SCI			2017	112						1112	1122		10.1016/j.procs.2017.08.138				11	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Computer Science, Information Systems; Computer Science, Interdisciplinary Applications	Computer Science	BJ1ZU	WOS:000418466000114		gold_or_bronze			2018-09-30	
