PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Qi, F				Qi, Feng			Integral representations for multivariate logarithmic polynomials	JOURNAL OF COMPUTATIONAL AND APPLIED MATHEMATICS			English	Article						Multivariate logarithmic polynomial; Generating function; Completely monotonic function; Bernstein function; Integral representation; Levy-Khintchine representation	2ND KIND	In the paper, by induction and recursively, the author proves that the generating function of multivariate logarithmic polynomials and its reciprocal are a Bernstein function and a completely monotonic function respectively, establishes a Levy-Khintchine representation for the generating function of multivariate logarithmic polynomials, deduces an integral representation for multivariate logarithmic polynomials, presents an integral representation for the reciprocal of the generating function of multivariate logarithmic polynomials, computes real and imaginary parts for the generating function of multivariate logarithmic polynomials, derives two integral formulas, and denies the uniform convergence of a known integral representation for Bernstein functions. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.	[Qi, Feng] Henan Polytech Univ, Inst Math, Jiaozuo 454010, Henan, Peoples R China; [Qi, Feng] Inner Mongolia Univ Nationalities, Coll Math, Tongliao 028043, Inner Mongolia, Peoples R China; [Qi, Feng] Tianjin Polytech Univ, Coll Sci, Dept Math, Tianjin 300387, Peoples R China	Qi, F (reprint author), Henan Polytech Univ, Inst Math, Jiaozuo 454010, Henan, Peoples R China.	qifeng618@gmail.com	Qi, Feng/G-2455-2012	Qi, Feng/0000-0001-6239-2968				18	0	0	6	12	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0377-0427	1879-1778		J COMPUT APPL MATH	J. Comput. Appl. Math.	JUL	2018	336						54	62		10.1016/j.cam.2017.11.047				9	Mathematics, Applied	Mathematics	FW8FP	WOS:000425565100004					2018-09-30	
