PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Kramarova, M; Dulina, L; Cechova, I		Bujnak, J; Guagliano, M		Kramarova, Miroslava; Dulina, Luboslav; Cechova, Ivana			Forklift workers strain of spine at industrial logistics in depending on human work posture	12TH INTERNATIONAL SCIENTIFIC CONFERENCE OF YOUNG SCIENTISTS ON SUSTAINABLE, MODERN AND SAFE TRANSPORT	Procedia Engineering				12th International Scientific Conference of Young Scientists on Sustainable, Modern and Safe Transport	MAY 31-JUN 02, 2017	High Tatras, SLOVAKIA	Univ Zilina				The article provides information about the dangerous logistic activities in a company, where a worker is exposed to an excessive load to the musculoskeletal system. It describes the dependence between the operator's load parameter during his control of a forklift and his subjective reaction to this load parameter in the form of strain. Evaluation of the operator's strain is based on the force that is exerted on the intervertebral segment L4 / L5 and the muscles in the spine. It also provides information about values of the operator's awkward postures, differing from the neutral working posture during a specific work activity that's hazardous. Subsequently, the article defines the optimal range of parameters for an operator, during his control of a forklift, within which he doesn't get into non-physiological work postures associated with discomfort. (C) 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.y					Cechova, Ivana/0000-0002-8705-3222												1877-7058						2017	192						486	491		10.1016/j.proeng.2017.06.084								WOS:000404958000084						
