PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Goodhead, DT				Goodhead, D. T.			CLASSICAL APPROACHES TO MICRODOSIMETRY, WITH EXAMPLE OF USE IN RADIATION PROTECTION, MEDICINE AND MECHANISTIC UNDERSTANDING	RADIATION PROTECTION DOSIMETRY					16th International Symposium on Microdosimetry (MICROS)	OCT 20-25, 2013	Trevisto, ITALY	INFN, Lab Nazl Legnaro, NASA, Johnson Space Ctr, Univ Nevada, Houston & Hlth Phys & Diagnost Sci Dept, Int Commiss Radiat Units & Measurements, Univ Oxford, Oxford Inst Radiat Oncol				Microdosimetry is the study and application of the microscopic features and stochastics of ionising radiations that cannot be described by the average macroscopic quantity absorbed dose. Microdosimetry is intimately related to radiation quality, but it also encompasses the inhomogeneities of interactions and energy depositions within a single radiation type. A variety of past and current approaches will be summarised and some examples given of implications to radiation protection and medicine, as well as to basic mechanistic studies of radiation effects.																	0144-8420	1742-3406				SEP	2015	166	1-4					276	281		10.1093/rpd/ncv194								WOS:000361806600057	25897134					
