PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Allevato, A; Sharp, A; Pryor, M			IEEE	Allevato, Adam; Sharp, Andrew; Pryor, Mitch			Getting the Shot: Socially-Aware Viewpoints for Autonomously Observing Tasks	2017 IEEE WORKSHOP ON ADVANCED ROBOTICS AND ITS SOCIAL IMPACTS	IEEE Workshop on Advanced Robotics and its Social Impacts		English	Proceedings Paper	IEEE Workshop on Advanced Robotics and its Social Impacts (ARSO)	MAR 08-10, 2017	Austin, TX	IEEE			ROBOTIC CAMERAMAN	In this work, we present an algorithm for autonomously determining the appropriate location from which to observe a human or robot agent (actor) while it completes a task in dynamic environments. We develop theory for selecting such a location using forward physical simulation of randomly-selected candidate viewpoints. The simulated points provide obstacle avoidance, and by incorporating a modified version of the Social Force Model, candidate viewpoints adjust themselves so that they do not encroach on the actor's personal space and/or safety region. The best observer position is chosen from these candidates to provide the most complete view of the task volume, taking into account the occlusion caused by the actor itself. We show that our algorithm works under a variety of task volume configurations, actor types (human and robot), and environmental constraints. Finally, the paper shows the results of hardware deployment on a two-robot system-one observer, and one actor. The paper concludes by examining the social impacts of deploying autonomous observation algorithms on real-world systems.	[Allevato, Adam; Sharp, Andrew; Pryor, Mitch] Univ Texas Austin, Dept Mech Engn, Austin, TX 78712 USA	Allevato, A (reprint author), Univ Texas Austin, Dept Mech Engn, Austin, TX 78712 USA.	allevato@utexas.edu; asharp@utexas.edu; mpryor@utexas.edu			Integrated University Program Graduate Fellowship; Los Alamos National Laboratory	This material is based upon work supported under an Integrated University Program Graduate Fellowship and Los Alamos National Laboratory. We thank Benjamin Ebersole for providing hardware support.		25	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2162-7568			IEEE WORK ADV ROBOT			2017														6	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic; Robotics	Computer Science; Engineering; Robotics	BJ7CH	WOS:000427050500019					2018-10-14	
