PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Walsh, B; Tian, F; Tourville, JA; Yucel, MA; Kuczek, T; Bostian, AJ				Walsh, B.; Tian, F.; Tourville, J. A.; Yucel, M. A.; Kuczek, T.; Bostian, A. J.			Hemodynamics of speech production: An fNIRS investigation of children who stutter	SCIENTIFIC REPORTS			English	Article							NEAR-INFRARED SPECTROSCOPY; TRANSCRANIAL MAGNETIC STIMULATION; POSITRON-EMISSION-TOMOGRAPHY; SUPERIOR TEMPORAL GYRUS; VOXEL-BASED MORPHOMETRY; BROCAS AREA; NEUROANATOMICAL DIFFERENCES; LANGUAGE PRODUCTION; SYLLABLE PRODUCTION; MOTOR CONTROL	Stuttering affects nearly 1% of the population worldwide and often has life-altering negative consequences, including poorer mental health and emotional well-being, and reduced educational and employment achievements. Over two decades of neuroimaging research reveals clear anatomical and physiological differences in the speech neural networks of adults who stutter. However, there have been few neurophysiological investigations of speech production in children who stutter. Using functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS), we examined hemodynamic responses over neural regions integral to fluent speech production including inferior frontal gyrus, premotor cortex, and superior temporal gyrus during a picture description task. Thirty-two children (16 stuttering and 16 controls) aged 7-11 years participated in the study. We found distinctly different speech-related hemodynamic responses in the group of children who stutter compared to the control group. Whereas controls showed significant activation over left dorsal inferior frontal gyrus and left premotor cortex, children who stutter exhibited deactivation over these left hemisphere regions. This investigation of neural activation during natural, connected speech production in children who stutter demonstrates that in childhood stuttering, atypical functional organization for speech production is present and suggests promise for the use of fNIRS during natural speech production in future research with typical and atypical child populations.	[Walsh, B.; Bostian, A. J.] Purdue Univ, Dept Speech Language & Hearing Sci, W Lafayette, IN 47907 USA; [Tian, F.] Univ Texas Arlington, Dept Bioengn, Arlington, TX 76019 USA; [Tourville, J. A.] Boston Univ, Dept Speech Language & Hearing Sci, Boston, MA 02215 USA; [Yucel, M. A.] Harvard Med Sch, Dept Radiol, Massachusetts Gen Hosp, MGH HST Athinoula A Martinos Ctr Biomed Imaging, Charlestown, MA USA; [Kuczek, T.] Purdue Univ, Dept Stat, W Lafayette, IN 47907 USA	Walsh, B (reprint author), Purdue Univ, Dept Speech Language & Hearing Sci, W Lafayette, IN 47907 USA.	bridget@purdue.edu		Tourville, Jason/0000-0002-7197-2427	National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders (NIDCD) [R03 DC013402]	We wish to thank Anne Smith for her advice throughout the project and for reviewing the final draft of the manuscript. We are grateful to Christy Ludlow for her suggestions and guidance during the initial stages of this project, as well as for reviewing preliminary findings. Special thanks to Barb Brown and all of the members of the Purdue Stuttering Project for their help recruiting participants. This research was supported by the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders (NIDCD Grant R03 DC013402) awarded to Bridget Walsh. Lastly, we are grateful to all of the children and their families whose participation made this research possible.		102	3	3	1	8	NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP	LONDON	MACMILLAN BUILDING, 4 CRINAN ST, LONDON N1 9XW, ENGLAND	2045-2322			SCI REP-UK	Sci Rep	JUN 22	2017	7								4034	10.1038/s41598-017-04357-6				13	Multidisciplinary Sciences	Science & Technology - Other Topics	EY3MF	WOS:000403874900017	28642548	gold			2018-10-15	
