PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Migliaccio, R; Boutet, C; Valabregue, R; Ferrieux, S; Nogues, M; Lehericy, S; Dormont, D; Levy, R; Dubois, B; Teichmann, M				Migliaccio, Raffaella; Boutet, Claire; Valabregue, Romain; Ferrieux, Sophie; Nogues, Marie; Lehericy, Stephane; Dormont, Didier; Levy, Richard; Dubois, Bruno; Teichmann, Marc			The Brain Network of Naming: A Lesson from Primary Progressive Aphasia	PLOS ONE			English	Article							ANTERIOR TEMPORAL INVOLVEMENT; SEMANTIC DEMENTIA; LEXICAL RETRIEVAL; SPEECH PRODUCTION; 3 VARIANTS; WORD; LANGUAGE; ANATOMY; MRI; PERFORMANCE	Objective Word finding depends on the processing of semantic and lexical information, and it involves an intermediate level for mapping semantic-to-lexical information which also subserves lexical-to-semantic mapping during word comprehension. However, the brain regions implementing these components are still controversial and have not been clarified via a comprehensive lesion model encompassing the whole range of language-related cortices. Primary progressive aphasia (PPA), for which anomia is thought to be the most common sign, provides such a model, but the exploration of cortical areas impacting naming in its three main variants and the underlying processing mechanisms is still lacking. Methods We addressed this double issue, related to language structure and PPA, with thirty patients (11 semantic, 12 logopenic, 7 agrammatic variant) using a picture-naming task and voxel-based morphometry for anatomo-functional correlation. First, we analyzed correlations for each of the three variants to identify the regions impacting naming in PPA and to disentangle the core regions of word finding. We then combined the three variants and correlation analyses for naming (semantic-to-lexical mapping) and single-word comprehension (lexical-to-semantic mapping), predicting an overlap zone corresponding to a bidirectional lexical-semantic hub. Results and Conclusions Our results showed that superior portions of the left temporal pole and left posterior temporal cortices impact semantic and lexical naming mechanisms in semantic and logopenic PPA, respectively. In agrammatic PPA naming deficits were rare, and did not correlate with any cortical region. Combined analyses revealed a cortical overlap zone in superior/middle mid-temporal cortices, distinct from the two former regions, impacting bidirectional binding of lexical and semantic information. Altogether, our findings indicate that lexical/semantic word processing depends on an anterior-posterior axis within lateral-temporal cortices, including an anatomically intermediate hub dedicated to lexical-semantic integration. Within this axis our data reveal the underpinnings of anomia in the PPA variants, which is of relevance for both diagnosis and future therapy strategies.	[Migliaccio, Raffaella; Boutet, Claire; Valabregue, Romain; Lehericy, Stephane; Levy, Richard; Dubois, Bruno; Teichmann, Marc] UMR INSERM CNRS UPMC 1127, Inst Cerveau & Moelle Epiniere, Paris, France; [Migliaccio, Raffaella; Ferrieux, Sophie; Nogues, Marie; Dubois, Bruno; Teichmann, Marc] Hop La Pitie Salpetriere, AP HP, Natl Reference Ctr PPA & Rare Dementias, Dept Neurol, Paris, France; [Boutet, Claire; Valabregue, Romain; Lehericy, Stephane] Ctr Neuroimagerie Rech CENIR, Inst Cerveau & Moelle Epiniere, Paris, France; [Dormont, Didier] Univ Paris 06, INSERM, UMR S 678, Paris, France; [Dormont, Didier] Hop La Pitie Salpetriere, AP HP, Serv Neuroradiol Diagnost & Fonct, Paris, France; [Levy, Richard] Hop St Antoine, AP HP, Dept Neurol, F-75571 Paris, France	Teichmann, M (reprint author), UMR INSERM CNRS UPMC 1127, Inst Cerveau & Moelle Epiniere, Paris, France.; Teichmann, M (reprint author), Hop La Pitie Salpetriere, AP HP, Natl Reference Ctr PPA & Rare Dementias, Dept Neurol, Paris, France.	marc.teichmann@psl.aphp.fr	Levy, Richard/D-8411-2011		"France Alzheimer" Foundation; "Philippe Chatrier" Foundation	We would like to thank Dalila Samri, Tiffany Landure and Richard Gnassounou for assessing patients with general cognitive tests. Raffaella Migliaccio was supported by the "France Alzheimer" and "Philippe Chatrier" Foundations; however no specific funding for this study was received by the author.		60	7	7	1	19	PUBLIC LIBRARY SCIENCE	SAN FRANCISCO	1160 BATTERY STREET, STE 100, SAN FRANCISCO, CA 94111 USA	1932-6203			PLOS ONE	PLoS One	FEB 22	2016	11	2							e0148707	10.1371/journal.pone.0148707				17	Multidisciplinary Sciences	Science & Technology - Other Topics	DF3VL	WOS:000371276100022	26901052	gold			2018-10-15	
