PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Su, S; Chen, LB; Zhang, ZM; Han, YB		Wang, G; Han, Y; Perez, GM		Su, Shen; Liu, Chen; Zhang, Zhongmei; Han, Yanbo			A Lightweight Model for Stream Sensor Data Service	ADVANCES IN SERVICES COMPUTING	Lecture Notes in Computer Science				10th International Conference on Asia-Pacific Services Computing (APSCC)	NOV 16-18, 2016	Zhangjiajie, PEOPLES R CHINA	Cent S Univ, Guangzhou Univ, Jishou Univ, N China Univ Technol, Springer, Huazhong Univ Sci & Technol, Sch Informat Sci & Engn, Serv Soc				The current Sensor Networks are generally domain-specific and task-oriented, tailored for particular applications with little possibility of sharing and reusing sensor data for different applications. The servitization of stream sensor data is an effective solution for sharing and reusing sensor data resources. Considering the limitations of existing methods on processing large-scale stream data and concurrent requests, this paper proposes a lightweight model for stream sensor data service, which processes sensor stream data with service modeling operations, and distributes data based on Pub/Sub mechanism. This paper fulfills the encapsulation by utilizing event-driven mechanism for stream data service processing, using SparkStreaming framework to process sensor events, and improving traditional matching-tree algorithm to distribute stream data efficiently. Finally, we evaluate our approach through experiments, and the stream data service can handle multiple requests and deliver data to corresponding applications in milliseconds level.																	0302-9743		978-3-319-49178-3; 978-3-319-49177-6				2016	10065						329	342		10.1007/978-3-319-49178-3_26								WOS:000389690900026						
