PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Vijayalakshmi, K; Aparna, S; Gopal, G; Hans, WJ			IEEE	Vijayalakshmi, K.; Aparna, S.; Gopal, Gayatri; Hans, W. Jino			Handwritten Character Recognition Using Diagonal-Based Feature Extraction	2017 2ND IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS, SIGNAL PROCESSING AND NETWORKING (WISPNET)					2nd IEEE International Conference on Wireless Communications, Signal Processing and Networking (WiSPNET)	MAR 22-24, 2017	Chennai, INDIA	IEEE, IEEE Commun Soc, SSN, iNSERB INDIA, Aconf, ISRO Bangalore, Pearson India Educ Serv Private Ltd, IEEE MAS Sect, IEEE Commun Madras Chapter, DST SERB New Delhi				This paper proposes a diagonal feature-based handwritten character recognition, using multi-layered feed forward neural network with back-propagation algorithm. The pixel information along the two diagonals is primarily extracted and used for recognition. The system is trained and tested on handwritten digits, English lower case character set and Tamil character database and their classification accuracy is compared. Finally, the recognition complexity of the fonts is also analyzed by testing the system with all the image pixels and the pixels along the central horizontal and vertical span.																			978-1-5090-4442-9				2017							1178	1181										WOS:000428513600217						
