PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Zeng, XH; Liu, BG; Zhou, M				Zeng, Xian-Hua; Liu, Bang-Gui; Zhou, Meng			Understanding and Generating Ultrasound Image Description	JOURNAL OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY			English	Article						ultrasound image; fine-grained classification; image captioning		To understand the content of ultrasound images more conveniently and more quickly, in this paper, we propose a coarse-to-fine ultrasound image captioning ensemble model, which can automatically generate the annotation text that is composed of relevant n-grams to describe the disease information in the ultrasound images. First, the organs in the ultrasound images are detected by the coarse classification model. Second, the ultrasound images are encoded by the corresponding fine-grained classification model according to the organ labels. Finally, we input the encoding vectors to the language generation model, and the language generation model generates automatically annotation text to describe the disease information in the ultrasound images. In our experiments, the encoding model can obtain the high accuracy rate in the ultrasound image recognition. And the language generation model can automatically generate high-quality annotation text. In practical applications, the coarse-to-fine ultrasound image captioning ensemble model can help patients and doctors obtain the well understanding of the contents of ultrasound images.	[Zeng, Xian-Hua; Liu, Bang-Gui; Zhou, Meng] Chongqing Univ Posts & Telecommun, Sch Comp Sci & Technol, Chongqing 400065, Peoples R China	Zeng, XH (reprint author), Chongqing Univ Posts & Telecommun, Sch Comp Sci & Technol, Chongqing 400065, Peoples R China.	zengxh@cqupt.edu.cn; 452246871@qq.com; 314444586@qq.com			National Natural Science Foundation of China [61672120]; Chongqing Natural Science Foundation Program of China [cstc2015jcyjA40036]; Postgraduate Scientific Research and Innovation Project of Chongqing of China [CYS17224]	This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China under Grant No. 61672120, the Chongqing Natural Science Foundation Program of China under Grant No. cstc2015jcyjA40036, and Postgraduate Scientific Research and Innovation Project of Chongqing of China under Grant No. CYS17224.		44	0	0	5	5	SCIENCE PRESS	BEIJING	16 DONGHUANGCHENGGEN NORTH ST, BEIJING 100717, PEOPLES R CHINA	1000-9000	1860-4749		J COMPUT SCI TECH-CH	J. Comput. Sci. Technol.	SEP	2018	33	5					1086	1100		10.1007/s11390-018-1874-8				15	Computer Science, Hardware & Architecture; Computer Science, Software Engineering	Computer Science	GT5QP	WOS:000444564800014					2018-12-09	
