PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Zhu, XS; Qian, YJ; Zhao, XF; Sun, B; Sun, Y				Zhu, Xinshan; Qian, Yongjun; Zhao, Xianfeng; Sun, Biao; Sun, Ya			A deep learning approach to patch-based image inpainting forensics	SIGNAL PROCESSING-IMAGE COMMUNICATION			English	Article						Inpainting; Forensics; Convolutional neural network; Loss function; Compression	FORGERY DETECTION ALGORITHM; NEURAL-NETWORKS; OBJECT REMOVAL; FEATURES	Although image inpainting is now an effective image editing technique, limited work has been done for inpainting forensics. The main drawbacks of the conventional inpainting forensics methods lie in the difficulties on inpainting feature extraction and the very high computational cost. In this paper, we propose a novel approach based on a convolutional neural network (CNN) to detect patch-based inpainting operation. Specifically, the CNN is built following the encoder decoder network structure, which allows us to predict the inpainting probability for each pixel in an image. To guide the CNN to automatically learn the inpainting features, a label matrix is generated for the CNN training by assigning a class label for each pixel of an image, and the designed weighted cross-entropy serves as the loss function. They further help to strongly supervise the CNN to capture the manipulation information rather than the image content features. By the established CNN, inpainting forensics does not need to consider feature extraction and classifier design, and use any postprocessing as in conventional forensics methods. They are combined into the unique framework and optimized simultaneously. Experimental results show that the proposed method achieves superior performance in terms of true positive rate, false positive rate and the running time, as compared with state-of-the-art methods for inpainting forensics, and is very robust against JPEG compression and scaling manipulations.	[Zhu, Xinshan; Qian, Yongjun; Sun, Biao; Sun, Ya] Tianjin Univ, Sch Elect & Informat Engn, Tianjin 300072, Peoples R China; [Zhu, Xinshan; Zhao, Xianfeng] Chinese Acad Sci, State Key Lab Informat Secur, Inst Informat Engn, Beijing 100093, Peoples R China	Sun, B (reprint author), Tianjin Univ, Sch Elect & Informat Engn, Tianjin 300072, Peoples R China.	xszhu@tju.edu.cn; sunbiao@tju.edu.cn			National Natural Science Foundation of China [60803122, 61401303, 61573253]; China Scholarship Fund [201506255067]; Opening Project of State Key Laboratory of Information Security [2017-MS-11]; Seed Foundation of Tianjin University [2017XZY-0090, 2018XZC-0033]	This study was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 60803122, 61401303, and 61573253), by the China Scholarship Fund (Grant No. 201506255067), by the Opening Project of State Key Laboratory of Information Security (Grant No. 2017-MS-11), and by the Seed Foundation of Tianjin University (Grant No. 2017XZY-0090 and 2018XZC-0033).		44	0	0	9	9	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0923-5965	1879-2677		SIGNAL PROCESS-IMAGE	Signal Process.-Image Commun.	SEP	2018	67						90	99		10.1016/j.image.2018.05.015				10	Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Engineering	GQ2LT	WOS:000441487200009					2018-10-15	
