PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Zheng, YW; Sheng, H; Liu, Y; Lv, K; Ke, W; Xiong, Z				Zheng, Yanwei; Sheng, Hao; Liu, Yang; Lv, Kai; Ke, Wei; Xiong, Zhang			Learning Irregular Space Transformation for Person Re-Identification	IEEE ACCESS			English	Article						Irregular space transformation; discriminative power enhancement; convolutional neural networks; person re-identification	FEATURES	Person re-identification (ReID) classifies the discriminative features of different people. Human perception usually depends on the minority of discriminative colors to classify targets, rather than the majority of mutual colors. ReID uses a small number of fixed cameras, which create a small account of similar backgrounds, leading to the majority of background pixels becoming non-discriminative (this is expanded in the feature map). This paper analyzes the distributions of feature maps to discover their different discriminative power. It also collects statistics that classify feature map values into individual ones and general ones according to the deviation of the mean value on each mini-batch. Finally, our findings introduce a learning irregular space transformation model in convolutional neural networks by enlarging the individual variance while reducing the general one to enhance the discrimination of features. We demonstrate our theories as valid on various public data sets, and achieve competitive results via quantitative evaluation.	[Zheng, Yanwei; Sheng, Hao; Liu, Yang; Lv, Kai; Xiong, Zhang] Beihang Univ, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, State Key Lab Software Dev Environm, Beijing 100191, Peoples R China; [Ke, Wei] Macau Polytech Inst, Sch Publ Adm, Macau 999078, Peoples R China	Sheng, H (reprint author), Beihang Univ, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, State Key Lab Software Dev Environm, Beijing 100191, Peoples R China.	shenghao@buaa.edu.cn		Liu, Yang/0000-0001-9698-9551	National Key R&D Program of China [2016QY01W0200]; National Natural Science Foundation of China [61472019]; Macao Science and Technology Development Fund [138/2016/A3]; Open Fund of the State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment [SKLSDE-2017ZX-09]; Project of Experimental Verification of the Basic Commonness and Key Technical Standards of the Industrial Internet Network Architecture; Technology Innovation Fund of China Electronic Technology Group Corporation	This work was supported in part by the National Key R&D Program of China under Grant 2016QY01W0200, in part by the National Natural Science Foundation of China under Grant 61472019, in part by the Macao Science and Technology Development Fund under Grant 138/2016/A3, in part by the Open Fund of the State Key Laboratory of Software Development Environment under Grant SKLSDE-2017ZX-09, in part by the Project of Experimental Verification of the Basic Commonness and Key Technical Standards of the Industrial Internet Network Architecture, and in part by the Technology Innovation Fund of China Electronic Technology Group Corporation.		66	0	0	2	2	IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC	PISCATAWAY	445 HOES LANE, PISCATAWAY, NJ 08855-4141 USA	2169-3536			IEEE ACCESS	IEEE Access		2018	6						53214	53225		10.1109/ACCESS.2018.2871149				12	Computer Science, Information Systems; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic; Telecommunications	Computer Science; Engineering; Telecommunications	GX7ZJ	WOS:000448000000001		DOAJ Gold			2018-12-09	
