PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Almodfer, R; Xiong, SW; Mudhsh, M; Duan, PF			IEEE	Almodfer, Rolla; Xiong, Shengwu; Mudhsh, Mohammed; Duan, Pengfei			Enhancing AlexNet for Arabic Handwritten words Recognition Using Incremental Dropout	2017 IEEE 29TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON TOOLS WITH ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (ICTAI 2017)	Proceedings-International Conference on Tools With Artificial Intelligence		English	Proceedings Paper	IEEE 29th International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence (ICTAI)	NOV 06-08, 2017	Boston, MA	IEEE, IEEE Comp Soc		Arabic handwritten; AlexNet; Overfitting; Dropout		Currently, the growth of mobile technologies, lead to a necessity to develop handwritten recognition applications. While the recognition of handwritten Latin and Chinese has been extensively investigated using various techniques, so little works have been done on Arabic handwritten recognition, and none of the existing techniques is accurate enough for practical application. Over the past few years, deeper convolutional neural networks (CNNs) have widely been employed for improving handwritten recognition performance. In this paper, we enhance the popular AlexNet for Arabic Handwritten Words Recognition (HWR). By adopting a dropout regularization, we prevented our system against overfitting problem and reduced the error recognition rate. We also investigated ReLU and tanH activation functions performance in the fully connected layers. Through several settings of experiments using the benchmarking IFN/ENIT Database, we achieved a new state-of-the-art classification accuracy of 92.13% and 92.55%. Lastly, we compared our best result to those of previous state-of-the-art.	[Almodfer, Rolla; Xiong, Shengwu; Mudhsh, Mohammed; Duan, Pengfei] Wuhan Univ Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Technol, Wuhan 430070, Hubei, Peoples R China; [Xiong, Shengwu; Duan, Pengfei] Wuhan Univ Technol, Hubei Key Lab Transportat Internet Things, Wuhan 430070, Hubei, Peoples R China	Duan, PF (reprint author), Wuhan Univ Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Technol, Wuhan 430070, Hubei, Peoples R China.; Duan, PF (reprint author), Wuhan Univ Technol, Hubei Key Lab Transportat Internet Things, Wuhan 430070, Hubei, Peoples R China.	duanpf@whut.edu.cn			Science & Technology Pillar Program of Hubei Province [2014BAA146]; Nature Science Foundation of Hubei Province [2015CFA059]; Science and Technology Open Cooperation Pro-gram of Henan Province [152106000048]	This research was supported in part by Science & Technology Pillar Program of Hubei Province under Grant (#2014BAA146), Nature Science Foundation of Hubei Province under Grant (#2015CFA059), Science and Technology Open Cooperation Pro-gram of Henan Province under Grant (#152106000048).		24	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	1082-3409		978-1-5386-3876-7	PROC INT C TOOLS ART			2017							663	669		10.1109/ICTAI.2017.00106				7	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Computer Science; Engineering	BK3OG	WOS:000435294700095					2018-12-10	
