PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Xiong, YD; Lu, TW; Jiang, YY		Cao, Z; Wang, Y; Cai, C		Xiong Yudian; Lu Tongwei; Jiang Yongyuan			Chinese Character Recognition Based on Gabor Feature Extraction and CNN	MIPPR 2017: PATTERN RECOGNITION AND COMPUTER VISION	Proceedings of SPIE		English	Proceedings Paper	10th International Symposium on Multispectral Image Processing and Pattern Recognition (MIPPR) - Pattern Recognition and Computer Vision	OCT 28-29, 2017	Xiangyang, PEOPLES R CHINA	Huazhong Univ Sci & Technol, Hubei Univ Arts & Sci, Natl Key Lab Sci and Technol Multi Spectral Informat Proc, Hubei Assoc Automat		Chinese character recognition; CNN; Gabor feature extraction		As an important application in the field of text line recognition and office automation, Chinese character recognition has become an important subject of pattern recognition. However, due to the large number of Chinese characters and the complexity of its structure, there is a great difficulty in the Chinese character recognition. In order to solve this problem, this paper proposes a method of printed Chinese character recognition based on Gabor feature extraction and Convolution Neural Network(CNN). The main steps are preprocessing, feature extraction, training classification. First, the gray-scale Chinese character image is binarized and normalized to reduce the redundancy of the image data. Second, each image is convoluted with Gabor filter with different orientations, and the feature map of the eight orientations of Chinese characters is extracted. Third, the feature map through Gabor filters and the original image are convoluted with learning kernels, and the results of the convolution is the input of pooling layer. Finally, the feature vector is used to classify and recognition. In addition, the generalization capacity of the network is improved by Dropout technology. The experimental results show that this method can effectively extract the characteristics of Chinese characters and recognize Chinese characters.	[Xiong Yudian; Lu Tongwei; Jiang Yongyuan] Wuhan Inst Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, Wuhan 430205, Hubei, Peoples R China; [Xiong Yudian; Lu Tongwei; Jiang Yongyuan] Wuhan Inst Technol, Hubei Key Lab Intelligent Robot, Wuhan 430205, Hubei, Peoples R China	Xiong, YD (reprint author), Wuhan Inst Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, Wuhan 430205, Hubei, Peoples R China.; Xiong, YD (reprint author), Wuhan Inst Technol, Hubei Key Lab Intelligent Robot, Wuhan 430205, Hubei, Peoples R China.				science research foundation of Hubei Province, China [2015CFB281]; science research foundation of Wuhan Institute of Technology, China [12126031]; Graduate Innovation foundation of Wuhan Institute of Technology, China [CX2014089]	This work was supported by the science research foundation of Hubei Province, China (No. 2015CFB281), the science research foundation of Wuhan Institute of Technology, China (No. 12126031) and the Graduate Innovation foundation of Wuhan Institute of Technology, China (No. CX2014089).		9	0	0	2	2	SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING	BELLINGHAM	1000 20TH ST, PO BOX 10, BELLINGHAM, WA 98227-0010 USA	0277-786X	1996-756X	978-1-5106-1722-3; 978-1-5106-1721-6	PROC SPIE			2017	10609								UNSP 106091N	10.1117/12.2288374				5	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic; Optics	Computer Science; Engineering; Optics	BK2DP	WOS:000432543300058					2018-12-10	
