PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Zhuo, QZ; Li, QM; Yan, H; Qi, Y		Li, T; Lopez, LM; Li, Y		Zhuo, Qinzheng; Li, Qianmu; Yan, Han; Qi, Yong			Long Short-term Memory Neural Network for Network Traffic Prediction	2017 12TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS AND KNOWLEDGE ENGINEERING (IEEE ISKE)			English	Proceedings Paper	12th International Conference on Intelligent Systems and Knowledge Engineering (IEEE ISKE)	NOV 24-26, 2017	NanJing, PEOPLES R CHINA	IEEE, IEEE Syst, IEEE Comp Soc		Recurrent neural networks; Time series; Network traffic prediction		This paper proposes a model of neural network which can be used to combine Long Short Term Memory networks (LSTM) with Deep Neural Networks (DNN). Autocorrelation coefficient is added to model to improve the accuracy of prediction model. It can provide better than the other traditional precision of the model. And after considering the autocorrelation features, the neural network of LSTM and DNN has certain advantages in the accuracy of the large granularity data sets. Several experiments were held using real-world data to show effectivity of LSTM model and accuracy were improve with autocorrelation considered.	[Zhuo, Qinzheng; Li, Qianmu; Yan, Han; Qi, Yong] Nanjing Univ Sci & Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, Nanjing, Jiangsu, Peoples R China	Li, QM (reprint author), Nanjing Univ Sci & Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, Nanjing, Jiangsu, Peoples R China.	zhuo_jimmy@yeah.net; liqianmu@126.com; yanhan@njust.edu.cn; Qyong@njust.edu.cn			Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities [30916015104]; National key research and development program: key projects of international scientific and technological innovation cooperation between governments [2016Y FE0108000]; CERNET next generation internet technology innovation project [NGII20160122]; Project of ZTE Cooperation Research [2016ZTE04-11]; Jiangsu province key research and development program: Social development project [BE2017739]; Jiangsu province key research and development program: Industry outlook and common key technology projects [BE2017100]	This paper supported by The Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities (No. 30916015104); National key research and development program: key projects of international scientific and technological innovation cooperation between governments (No. 2016Y FE0108000); CERNET next generation internet technology innovation project (NGII20160122); The Project of ZTE Cooperation Research (2016ZTE04-11), Jiangsu province key research and development program: Social development project (BE2017739), Jiangsu province key research and development program: Industry outlook and common key technology projects (BE2017100).		20	0	0	1	1	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA			978-1-5386-1829-5				2017														6	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Computer Science; Engineering	BJ8CJ	WOS:000427969500100					2018-12-10	
