PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Ding, YL; Zhang, XL; Tang, JS			IEEE	Ding, Yulin; Zhang, Xiaolong; Tang, Jinshan			A Noisy Sparse Convolution Neural Network Based on Stacked Auto-encoders	2017 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SYSTEMS, MAN, AND CYBERNETICS (SMC)	IEEE International Conference on Systems Man and Cybernetics Conference Proceedings		English	Proceedings Paper	IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC)	OCT 05-08, 2017	Banff, CANADA	IEEE		deep learning; convolution neural networks; stacked auto-encoders; noisy auto-encoders; sparsity constrain	REPRESENTATIONS	Stacked auto-encoder is mainly used for image classification and it can extract valid information from data through unsupervised pre-training and supervised fine-tuning. This paper is intended to improve the accuracy of image classification, we constructed a 6-layer stacked convolution neural network (CNN) based on stacked auto-encoders. The constructed CNN can extract effective features for image classification through greedy layer-wise training. In order to make the constructed CNN to have strong robustness to noise, we added a noisy-layer in the pre-training stage. Adding the sparsity constraint can make the training of the CNN more effective, and can also reduce data redundancy. For classification applications, our experiments show that the final classification results of the proposed model is superior to the combination of auto-encoders and the noisy auto-encoders.	[Ding, Yulin; Zhang, Xiaolong; Tang, Jinshan] Wuhan Univ Sci & Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Technol, Wuhan, Hubei, Peoples R China; [Ding, Yulin; Zhang, Xiaolong; Tang, Jinshan] Intelligent Informat Proc & Real Time Ind Syst Hu, Wuhan, Hubei, Peoples R China; [Tang, Jinshan] Michigan Technol Univ, Sch Technol, Houghton, MI 49931 USA	Zhang, XL (reprint author), Wuhan Univ Sci & Technol, Sch Comp Sci & Technol, Wuhan, Hubei, Peoples R China.; Zhang, XL (reprint author), Intelligent Informat Proc & Real Time Ind Syst Hu, Wuhan, Hubei, Peoples R China.	xiaolong.zhang@wust.edu.cn			National Natural Science Foundation of China [61273225, 61273303, 61373109]; Program for Outstanding Young Science and Technology Innovation Teams in Higher Education Institutions of Hubei Province [T201202]; National "Twelfth Five-Year" Plan for Science & Technology Support [2012BAC22B01]	This work was supported in part by National Natural Science Foundation of China (61273225, 61273303, 61373109), Program for Outstanding Young Science and Technology Innovation Teams in Higher Education Institutions of Hubei Province (No. T201202), as well as National "Twelfth Five-Year" Plan for Science & Technology Support (2012BAC22B01).		9	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	1062-922X		978-1-5386-1645-1	IEEE SYS MAN CYBERN			2017							3457	3461						5	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Computer Science, Cybernetics	Computer Science	BJ7RJ	WOS:000427598703088					2018-12-10	
