PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Gong, ZQ; Zhong, P; Yu, Y; Hu, WD			IEEE	Gong, Zhiqiang; Zhong, Ping; Yu, Yang; Hu, Weidong			DIVERSIFIED DEEP STRUCTURAL METRIC LEARNING FOR LAND USE CLASSIFICATION IN REMOTE SENSING IMAGES	2017 IEEE INTERNATIONAL GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING SYMPOSIUM (IGARSS)	IEEE International Symposium on Geoscience and Remote Sensing IGARSS		English	Proceedings Paper	IEEE International Geoscience & Remote Sensing Symposium	JUL 23-28, 2017	Fort Worth, TX	Institute of Elect & Electron Engineers Geoscience & Remote Sensing Soc, IEEE, IEEE GRSS		Remote sensing image; deep structural metric learning; diversity; land use; classification		In this work, a diversified deep structural metric learning is proposed for remote sensing image classification. Firstly, a deep structural metric learning is introduced to take full advantage of structural information of training batches. Secondly, we impose a diversity regularization over the factors of deep structural metric learning to encourage them to be uncorrelated, such that each factor tends to model unique information during the training phase and all factors sums up to capture a larger proportion of information. The diversified model could benefit the classification of remote sensing images. Experiments are conducted on two real-world remote sensing image datasets to evaluate the effectiveness and wide applicability of the proposed approach. The results show that our proposed method can obtain comparable or even better results on remote sensing image classification when compared with the recent results.	[Gong, Zhiqiang; Zhong, Ping; Yu, Yang; Hu, Weidong] Natl Univ Def Technol, Sch Elect Sci & Engn, ATR Lab, Changsha 410073, Hunan, Peoples R China	Zhong, P (reprint author), Natl Univ Def Technol, Sch Elect Sci & Engn, ATR Lab, Changsha 410073, Hunan, Peoples R China.	zhongping@nudt.edu.cn			NSF of China [61671456, 61271439]; FANEDD [201243]; Program for New Century Excellent Talents in University [NECT-13-0164]	This work was supported by the NSF of China under Grant 61671456 and 61271439, FANEDD under Grant 201243, Program for New Century Excellent Talents in University under Grant NECT-13-0164.		10	0	0	1	1	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2153-6996		978-1-5090-4951-6	INT GEOSCI REMOTE SE			2017							1676	1679						4	Geosciences, Multidisciplinary; Remote Sensing	Geology; Remote Sensing	BJ6TY	WOS:000426954601212					2018-12-10	
