PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Ren, YZ; Zhao, P; Xu, ZL; Yao, DZ			IEEE	Ren, Yazhou; Zhao, Peng; Xu, Zenglin; Yao, Dezhong			Balanced Self-Paced Learning with Feature Corruption	2017 INTERNATIONAL JOINT CONFERENCE ON NEURAL NETWORKS (IJCNN)	IEEE International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)		English	Proceedings Paper	International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)	MAY 14-19, 2017	Anchorage, AK	Int Neurol Network Soc, IEEE Computat Intelligence Soc, Intel, BMI, Budapest Semester Cognit Sci			NOISE	Self-paced learning (SPL), a recently proposed learning strategy, which progressively adds instances to train from simplicity to complexity, could typically reduce the risk of achieving local optima. SPL selects instances based on their losses among the entire data set in each iteration. This probably causes that the selected instances are highly imbalanced, e.g., very few (even on) instances of some classes are chosen, and further negatively affects the training process. To address this issue, we propose a balanced self-paced learning (BSPL) scenario, which iteratively selects training samples based on their loss values from each class, instead of from the entire data set. From another perspective, learning with marginalized corrupted features is an approach to control overfitting by artificially corrupting the training data. However, feature corruption techniques typically lead to that the classification problem is non-convex and easily traps in local optima. To alleviate this, we propose balanced self-paced learning with feature corruption (BSPL-FC), which considers the instance sampling and feature corruption simultaneously. BSPL-FC first treats the feature corruption as a regularizer and then applies BSPL to solve the regularized classification problem. BSPL-FC inherently has advantages in controlling overfitting and avoiding local optima. Experimental results show the effectiveness of the proposed model.	[Ren, Yazhou; Zhao, Peng; Xu, Zenglin] Univ Elect Sci & Technol China, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, Big Data Res Ctr, Chengdu 611731, Sichuan, Peoples R China; [Ren, Yazhou; Yao, Dezhong] Univ Elect Sci & Technol China, Sch Life Sci & Technol, Minist Educ, Key Lab NeuroInformat, Chengdu 611731, Sichuan, Peoples R China	Ren, YZ (reprint author), Univ Elect Sci & Technol China, Sch Comp Sci & Engn, Big Data Res Ctr, Chengdu 611731, Sichuan, Peoples R China.; Ren, YZ (reprint author), Univ Elect Sci & Technol China, Sch Life Sci & Technol, Minist Educ, Key Lab NeuroInformat, Chengdu 611731, Sichuan, Peoples R China.	yazhou.ren@uestc.edu.cn; pzhao201@std.uestc.edu.cn; zlxu@uestc.edu.cn; dyao@uestc.edu.cn			Natural Science Foundation of China [61572111]; National High Technology Research and Development Program of China (863 Program) [2015AA015408]; joint Foundation of the Ministry of Education of China; China Mobile Communication Corporation [MCM20150505]; China Postdoctoral Science Foundation [2016M602674]; 985 Project of UESTC [A1098531023601041]; two Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of China [ZYGX2014J058, A03012023601042]	This paper was in part supported by Grants from the Natural Science Foundation of China (No. 61572111), the National High Technology Research and Development Program of China (863 Program) (No. 2015AA015408), the joint Foundation of the Ministry of Education of China and China Mobile Communication Corporation (No. MCM20150505), a Project funded by China Postdoctoral Science Foundation(No. 2016M602674), a 985 Project of UESTC (No. A1098531023601041) and two Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of China (Nos. ZYGX2014J058, A03012023601042).		33	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2161-4393		978-1-5090-6182-2	IEEE IJCNN			2017							2064	2071						8	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Computer Science, Hardware & Architecture; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Computer Science; Engineering	BJ6WL	WOS:000426968702042					2018-12-10	
