PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Qin, PD; Xu, WR; Guo, J			IEEE	Qin, Pengda; Xu, Weiran; Guo, Jun			Designing an Adaptive Attention Mechanism for Relation Classification	2017 INTERNATIONAL JOINT CONFERENCE ON NEURAL NETWORKS (IJCNN)	IEEE International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)		English	Proceedings Paper	International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)	MAY 14-19, 2017	Anchorage, AK	Int Neurol Network Soc, IEEE Computat Intelligence Soc, Intel, BMI, Budapest Semester Cognit Sci				Entity pair provide essential information for identifying relation type. Aiming at this characteristic, Position Feature is widely used in current relation classification systems to highlight the words close to them. However, semantic knowledge involved in entity pair has not been fully utilized. To overcome this issue, we propose an Entity-pair-based Attention Mechanism, which is specially designed for relation classification. Recently, attention mechanism significantly promotes the development of deep learning in NLP. Inspired by this, for specific instance(entity pair, sentence), the corresponding entity pair information is incorporated as prior knowledge to adaptively compute attention weights for generating sentence representation. Experimental results on SemEval-2010 Task 8 dataset show that our method outperforms most of the state-of-the-art models, without external linguistic features.	[Qin, Pengda; Xu, Weiran; Guo, Jun] Beijing Univ Posts & Telecommun, Sch Informat & Commun Engn, Beijing, Peoples R China	Qin, PD (reprint author), Beijing Univ Posts & Telecommun, Sch Informat & Commun Engn, Beijing, Peoples R China.	qinpengda@bupt.edu.cn; xuweiran@bupt.edu.cn; guojun@bupt.edu.cn			111 Project of China [B08004]; National Natural Science Foundation of China [61273217, 61300080]; Ph.D. Programs Foundation of Ministry of Education of China [20130005110004]	This work was supported by 111 Project of China under Grant no. B08004, the National Natural Science Foundation of China (61273217, 61300080), the Ph.D. Programs Foundation of Ministry of Education of China (20130005110004).		29	1	1	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2161-4393		978-1-5090-6182-2	IEEE IJCNN			2017							4356	4362						7	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Computer Science, Hardware & Architecture; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Computer Science; Engineering	BJ6WL	WOS:000426968704080					2018-12-10	
