PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Ramasamy, DL; Repo, E; Srivastava, V; Sillanpaa, M				Ramasamy, Deepika Lakshmi; Repo, Eveliina; Srivastava, Varsha; Sillanpaa, Mika			Chemically immobilized and physically adsorbed PAN/acetylacetone modified mesoporous silica for the recovery of rare earth elements from the waste water-comparative and optimization study	WATER RESEARCH												This study was aimed at the investigation of Rare Earth Element (REE) recovery from aqueous solution by silica gels with 1-(2-Pyridylazo) 2-naphthol (PAN) and acetyl acetone (Acac) modifications. The two different methods of silica gel chelation, such as chemical immobilization with the help of silane coupling agents (3-aminopropyl triethoxysilane (APTES) and 3-aminopropyl trimethoxysilane (APTMS) in this study) and direct physical adsorption onto the silica surface, is compared in terms of their REE removal efficiency. A comparative analysis between adsorption of different REEs for different silica gels is performed and the influence of parameters such as pH, contact time, temperature and initial concentration has been reported. The effect of calcined adsorbents on the adsorption process is also investigated. Characterization studies on silica gels by Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), Scanning electron microscopy (SEM), Brunauer-Emmett-Teller (BET), X-ray diffraction (XRD) and zeta potential analysis are performed to better understand the relation between physical/chemical attributes of the adsorbents and their impact on the adsorption process. The experimental results are evaluated and optimal conditions for REE adsorption are identified. Chemically immobilized gels demonstrated immense potential for all the REE under study except Sc, for which, physically, loaded gels seemed to be more efficient. The removal of REEs could be achieved at lower pHs by chemically immobilized PAN/Acac gels, making it suitable for many practical applications. The amine functionalized gels before chemical immobilization step were compared with PAN/Acac chemically immobilized gels in single as well as multi element system and the significance of chemical immobilization after amine functionalization is also stated. (C) 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.																	0043-1354					MAY 1	2017	114						264	276		10.1016/j.watres.2017.02.045								WOS:000397695800026	28254644					
