PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Anchordoquy, JP; Anchordoquy, JM; Pascua, AM; Nikoloff, N; Peral-Garcia, P; Furnus, CC				Anchordoquy, J. P.; Anchordoquy, J. M.; Pascua, A. M.; Nikoloff, N.; Peral-Garcia, P.; Furnus, C. C.			The copper transporter (SLC31A1/CTR1) is expressed in bovine spermatozoa and oocytes: Copper in IVF medium improves sperm quality	THERIOGENOLOGY												Adequate dietary intake of copper (Cu) is required for normal reproductive performance in cattle. The objective of this study was to investigate the pregnancy rates from cattle with deficient, marginal and adequate Cu plasma concentration at the beginning of artificial insemination protocol. Moreover, we determined Cu concentrations present in bovine oviductal fluid (OF), and the effects of Cu on fertilizing ability of bovine spermatozoa. Also, the presence of Cu transporter, SLC31A1 (also known as CTR1), in spermatozoa and in vitro matured oocyte were investigated. We found no differences in pregnancy rates among animals with adequate, marginal, and deficient Cu concentrations measured in plasma at the beginning of fixed-time artificial insemination (FTAI) protocol. Copper concentrations in OF were 383 +/- 2.17 mu g/dL (mean +/- SEM) regardless of cupremia levels. The addition of 40 mu g/dL Cu to IVF medium enhanced total and progressive motility, sperm viability, functional sperm membrane integrity (HOST), sperm zona binding, and pronuclear formation. On the other hand, the presence of Cu in IVF medium did not modify acrosome integrity and cleavage rates after IVF, but impaired blastocyst rates. Cu transporter SLC31A1 was detected in bovine spermatozoa in the apical segment of acrosome, and in the oocyte matured in vitro. In conclusion, the results obtained in the present study determined that cupremia levels at the beginning of FTAI protocol did not influence the pregnancy rates at 60 d after insemination. The presence of CTR1 in bovine mature oocyte and spermatozoa, as well as the beneficial effect of Cu on sperm quality would suggest an important role of this mineral during the fertilization process. (C) 2017 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.																	0093-691X	1879-3231				JUL 15	2017	97						124	133		10.1016/j.theriogenology.2017.04.037								WOS:000403386900017	28583595					
