PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Abdelfattah, AS; Abdelkader, T; EI-Horbaty, ESM			IEEE	Abdelfattah, Amr S.; Abdelkader, Tamer; EI-Horbaty, EI-Sayed M.			Reliable Web Services Approaches of Mobile Cloud Computing: A Comparative study	2015 IEEE SEVENTH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INTELLIGENT COMPUTING AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS (ICICIS)					IEEE Seventh International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Information Systems (ICICIS)	DEC 12-14, 2015	CAIRO, EGYPT					The Mobile intermittent wireless connectivity limits the evolution of the mobile landscape, such that this progress coupled with the ubiquitous nature of the Internet and the web services. The web service Reliability achieves the low overhead communication and retrieves the appropriate state response from the web service consumption. This paper discusses and analyzes the most recent approaches that achieve the reliability of web services consumed by mobile devices. Achieving the reliable web service consumption is tended to two approaches: Middleware approach and Mobile Agent (MA) approach. Both of them focus on ensuring the request execution under the communication limitations and services temporary unavailability.																			978-1-5090-1949-6				2015							217	223										WOS:000380470400033						
