PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Gronewold, TMA				Gronewold, Thomas M. A.			Surface acoustic wave sensors in the bioanalytical field: Recent trends and challenges	ANALYTICA CHIMICA ACTA			English	Review						surface acoustic wave sensor; developments; sensor chip; applications; biosensing techniques	INCORPORATING SILICON DIOXIDE; QUARTZ-CRYSTAL MICROBALANCE; VOLATILE ORGANIC-COMPOUNDS; CHEMICAL WARFARE AGENTS; LOVE-WAVE; SAW SENSOR; PLASMON RESONANCE; MASS SENSITIVITY; ELECTRONIC NOSE; PATTERN-RECOGNITION	This is a comparison of the latest developments in the emerging field of surface acoustic wave (SAW) sensors. Progress has been made particularly with regard to (sub-) microstructure technology and material sciences. Improvements are displayed based on the impact on a new generation of SAW sensors working efficiently in liquid media, from modeling to the fabrication steps of the individual components. It is explained, which obstacles have to be overcome for applications to the bioanalytical field. SAW sensors are shown to be extremely useful for the analysis of both small and large molecules as well as whole cells interacting with an immobilized binding partner. The output signal gives information about the pure mass loading, intrinsic properties of bound materials, or viscoelastic effects like structural rearrangements. Different setups are shown that minimize the influence of physical bulk effects on the sensor signal, e.g. salt content and viscosity. The choice of materials which can be used for sensible surfaces are presented, enabling the development of completely new coupling chemistries. Finally, the advantages compared to other biosensor technologies are pointed out. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.	CAESAR, Res Ctr, D-53175 Bonn, Germany	Gronewold, TMA (reprint author), CAESAR, Res Ctr, Ludwig Erhard Alle 2, D-53175 Bonn, Germany.	gronewold@caesar.de						148	134	135	4	71	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0003-2670	1873-4324		ANAL CHIM ACTA	Anal. Chim. Acta	NOV 12	2007	603	2					119	128		10.1016/j.aca.2007.09.056				10	Chemistry, Analytical	Chemistry	232VA	WOS:000251047000001	17963831				2018-10-29	
