PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Bhattarai, K; Prasad, PWC; Alsadoon, A; Pham, L; Elchouemi, A			IEEE	Bhattarai, Kritagya; Prasad, P. W. C.; Alsadoon, Abeer; Pham, L.; Elchouemi, A.			Experiments on the MFCC application in Speaker Recognition using Matlab	2017 SEVENTH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INFORMATION SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (ICIST2017)	International Conference on Information Science and Technology				7th International Conference on Information Science and Technology (ICIST)	APR 16-19, 2017	Da Nang, VIETNAM	City Univ Hong Kong, Vietnam Korea Friendship Informat Technol Coll, Hong Kong Web Soc, IEEE Syst, Man & Cybernet Soc				Speaker recognition is a very important research area where speech synthesis, and speech noise reduction are some of the major research areas. Speaker recognition is a new challenge for technologies. Many algorithms have been suggested and developed for feature extraction. This paper presents a feature extraction technique for speaker recognition using Mel Frequency Cepstral Coefficients (MFCC). Further, this paper evaluates experiments conducted along each step of the MFCC process. Finally, the paper compares hamming window and rectangular window technique based on the number of filters for accurate and efficient result in a Matlab environment. The result indicates that using a 32 filter with hamming window has more accuracy and efficiency compared to other windowing techniques and number of filters.																	2164-4357		978-1-5090-5401-5				2017							32	37										WOS:000403402600007						
