PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Sokolovs, A; Grigans, L; Dzelzkaleja, L; Majore, G; Bikulciene, L		Ginters, E; Schumann, M		Sokolovs, Alvis; Grigans, Linards; Dzelzkaleja, Laura; Majore, Ginta; Bikulciene, Liepa			Heat Recovery Technologies from Aerobic Bio-degradation: from Theoretical Finding to Modeling Results	ICTE IN REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT 2015	Procedia Computer Science				Conference on ICTE in Regional Development	DEC, 2015	Valmiera, LATVIA	ICTE				It is common knowledge that complete biomass aerobic (in the presence of oxygen) degradation releases the same amount of energy that was captured in the biomass cells during photosynthesis or feeding. If the bio-degradation process is managed in a way that there is an optimal moisture, oxygen and feedstock supply, a kind of bacteria - thermophilic - proliferate, and their metabolism processes can increase the biomass temperature to over 70 degrees C. However, the optimal temperature for these bacteria is about 60 degrees C, so the excess heat energy should be removed and could be used for heating. The purpose of this paper is to present a review of state of art of available technologies and research papers for heat recovery from aerobic bio-degradation. Modelling methods will be applied for theoretical investigation. The conclusions are that heat recovery from aerobic bio-degradation is not a well explored field and only a few papers are available where a prototype or experiments are presented exactly on heat recovery technologies from bio-degradation. On the other hand the process of biodegradation is well explored and some of the technologies for composting purposes use heat recovery to accelerate the process of composting. In the future it would be advisable to research and experiment in order to make prediction models for bacteria behaviour if the parameters are changed, and be able to automate the process. (C) 2015 Published by Elsevier B.V.																	1877-0509						2015	77						141	150		10.1016/j.procs.2015.12.371								WOS:000370939100019						
