PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Brucher, BLDM; Jamall, IS				Bruecher, Bjoern L. D. M.; Jamall, Ijaz S.			Cell-Cell Communication in the Tumor Microenvironment, Carcinogenesis, and Anticancer Treatment	CELLULAR PHYSIOLOGY AND BIOCHEMISTRY												The delineation of key molecular pathways has enhanced our knowledge of the biology of tumor microenvironment, tumor dissemination, and carcinogenesis. The complexities of cell cell communication and the possibilities for modulation provide new opportunities for treating cancers. Cells communicate by direct and indirect signaling. Direct cell-cell communication involves both, self-self-communication (intracrine and autocrine), and adjacent communication with nearby cells (juxtacrine), which themselves are regulated by distinct pathways. Indirect intercellular communication involves local communication over short distances (paracrine and synaptic signaling) or over large distances via hormones (endocrine). The essential components of cell cell communication involve communication junctions (Connexins, Plasmodesmata, Ion Channels, Chemical Synapses, and Pannexins), occluding junctions (Tight Junctions), and anchoring junctions (Adherens, Desmosomes, Focal Adhesions, and Hemidesmosomes). The communication pathways pass through junctions at physical cell cell attachments, and they go, as well, through the extracellular matrix (ECM) via the different transmembrane adhesion proteins (Cadherins and Integrins). We have here reviewed cell cell communication involving (1) the components of junctions and their dynamic interplay with the other aspects of communication, including (2) the tumor microenvironment and carcinogenesis, (3) coupling and migration, (4) the underlying cell cell and sub cellular communication mechanisms (signaling) of anticancer treatments, and finally, (5) aspects of recent research on cell cell communication. Copyrlght (C) 2014 S Karger AG, Basel				Brucher, Bjorn/C-3441-2008	Brucher, Bjorn/0000-0002-3930-6416												1015-8987	1421-9778					2014	34	2					213	243		10.1159/000362978								WOS:000343764600001	25034869					
