PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Khalilzadeh, N; Bin Saion, E; Mirabolghasemi, H; Bin Shaari, AH; Bin Hashim, M; Ahmad, MBJ; Ali, NM; Dehzangi, A				Khalilzadeh, Nasrin; Bin Saion, Elias; Mirabolghasemi, Hamed; Bin Shaari, Abdul Halim; Bin Hashim, Mansor; Ahmad, Mansor Bin H. J.; Ali, Noriah Mod; Dehzangi, Arash			Single step thermal treatment synthesis and characterization of lithium tetraborate nanophosphor	JOURNAL OF MATERIALS RESEARCH AND TECHNOLOGY-JMR&T			English	Article						Nanolithium tetraborate; Single step thermal treatment; PVP capping agent; Slow separation nucleation; Band gap		This study includes the synthesis of nano-sized lithium tetraborate by an innovative single step thermal treatment method and characterization of the products. The heating temperature for the synthesis was varied between 200 and 850 degrees C with the retention time of 2 h. Polyvinyl pyrrolidone (PVP) with different concentrations was used as surfactant. Characterization of the samples was achieved by thermogravimetric analysis (TGA), derivative thermogravimetry analysis (DTG), differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR), X-ray diffraction (XRD), transmission electron microscopy (TEM) techniques and UV-vis spectroscopy. Thermal analysis of initial solution allowed the optimization of the heat treatment program and showed that the thermal stability of samples is started at 460 C. FT-IR, XRD and TEM results proved the formation of pure nano-crystalline lithium tetraborate at temperature between 460 and 750 degrees C. Furthermore, the band gap investigation was performed using UV-vis spectra in the presence of different concentrations of PVP and in variety of calcination temperatures. The estimated optical bandgap was found to be between 5.2 and 6.2 eV. (C) 2015 Brazilian Metallurgical, Materials and Mining Association. Published by Elsevier Editora Ltda. All rights reserved.	[Khalilzadeh, Nasrin; Bin Saion, Elias; Bin Shaari, Abdul Halim] Univ Putra Malaysia, Fac Sci, Dept Phys, Serdang, Malaysia; [Mirabolghasemi, Hamed] Natl Univ Singapore, Dept Mat Sci & Engn, Singapore, Singapore; [Bin Hashim, Mansor] Univ Putra Malaysia, Inst Adv Technol, Serdang, Malaysia; [Ahmad, Mansor Bin H. J.] Univ Putra Malaysia, Fac Sci, Dept Chem, Serdang, Malaysia; [Ali, Noriah Mod] Agensi Nuklear Malaysia, Hlth Phys Grp, Bangi, Kajang, Malaysia; [Dehzangi, Arash] Natl Univ Malaysia, Inst Microengn & Nanoelect, Bangi, Malaysia	Khalilzadeh, N (reprint author), Univ Putra Malaysia, Fac Sci, Dept Phys, Serdang, Malaysia.	nkhalilzadeh40@gmail.com	Dehzangi, Arash/H-6493-2013	Dehzangi, Arash/0000-0001-5043-2678; shaari, abdul halim/0000-0001-6729-630X	Ministry of Higher Education of Malaysia	This work was granted by the Ministry of Higher Education of Malaysia under the FRGS and RUGS grants. The authors would be appreciated for the attention and collaboration of the staff of the Faculty of Science, the Faculty of Engineering, and Bioscience Institute of University Putra Malaysia. Moreover, we also would like to thank to the staff of the Nuclear Agency of Malaysia for allowing the use of their facilities. Furthermore, so many thanks to the staff of school of Applied Physics of University Kebangsaan Malaysia for their cooperation.		28	4	4	0	0	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	2238-7854	2214-0697		J MATER RES TECHNOL	J. Mater. Res. Technol-JMRT	JAN-MAR	2016	5	1					37	44		10.1016/j.jmrt.2015.05.005				8	Materials Science, Multidisciplinary; Metallurgy & Metallurgical Engineering	Materials Science; Metallurgy & Metallurgical Engineering	DQ9IM	WOS:000379523600006		DOAJ Gold			2018-11-09	
