PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Kaplan, AP; Gimenez-Arnau, AM; Saini, SS				Kaplan, A. P.; Gimenez-Arnau, A. M.; Saini, S. S.			Mechanisms of action that contribute to efficacy of omalizumab in chronic spontaneous urticaria	ALLERGY			English	Review						chronic idiopathic urticaria; chronic spontaneous urticaria; omalizumab	CHRONIC IDIOPATHIC URTICARIA; FC-EPSILON-RI; CHRONIC IDIOPATHIC/SPONTANEOUS URTICARIA; MAST-CELL ACTIVATION; AFFINITY IGE RECEPTOR; DELAYED PRESSURE URTICARIA; LATE-PHASE REACTIONS; ANTI-IGE; HISTAMINE-RELEASE; HUMAN BASOPHILS	The monoclonal anti-immunoglobulin E (IgE) antibody, omalizumab, was the first drug approved for use in patients with chronic idiopathic/spontaneous urticaria (CIU/CSU) who remain symptomatic despite H-1-antihistamine treatment. Omalizumab binds to free IgE, which lowers free IgE levels and causes Fc epsilon RI receptors on basophils and mast cells to be downregulated. It has been shown to improve symptoms of CIU/CSU, but its mechanism of action is not currently understood. Potential mechanisms in CIU/CSU include reducing mast cell releasability, reversing basopenia and improving basophil IgE receptor function, reducing activity of IgG autoantibodies against Fc epsilon RI and IgE, reducing activity of IgE autoantibodies against an antigen or autoantigen that has yet to be definitively identified, reducing the activity of intrinsically abnormal' IgE, and decreasing in vitro coagulation abnormalities associated with disease activity. However, none of these theories alone or in combination fully account for the pattern of symptom improvement seen with omalizumab therapy, and therefore, no one mechanism is likely to be the definitive mechanism of action. Additional research is needed to further clarify the involvement of omalizumab in relieving symptoms associated with the complex, multifactorial pathogenesis of CIU/CSU.	[Kaplan, A. P.] Med Univ South Carolina, Div Pulm & Crit Care Med Allergy & Clin Immunol, Dept Med, Charleston, SC USA; [Gimenez-Arnau, A. M.] Univ Autonoma Barcelona, Inst Mar Invest Med, Dept Dermatol, Hosp del Mar, Barcelona, Spain; [Saini, S. S.] Johns Hopkins Asthma & Allergy Ctr, Baltimore, MD USA	Kaplan, AP (reprint author), Med Univ South Carolina, Div Pulm Crit Care Med Allergy & Clin Immunol, 1879 Savage Rd, Charleston, SC 29425 USA.	kaplana@musc.edu			Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corporation, East Hanover, NJ, USA; Genentech, Inc., South San Francisco, CA, USA	Medical writing and editorial assistance in the development of this manuscript were provided by Sarah Thornburg at JK Associates, Inc., Conshohocken, PA, USA, a part of the Fishawack Group of Companies, and this service was supported by Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corporation, East Hanover, NJ, USA, and Genentech, Inc., South San Francisco, CA, USA.		142	26	26	3	12	WILEY	HOBOKEN	111 RIVER ST, HOBOKEN 07030-5774, NJ USA	0105-4538	1398-9995		ALLERGY	Allergy	APR	2017	72	4					519	533		10.1111/all.13083				15	Allergy; Immunology	Allergy; Immunology	EP6KW	WOS:000397489400002	27861988	Bronze, Green Accepted			2018-11-09	
