PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Liu, CF; Lu, L; Zhang, LX; Bai, Y; Medina, A; Rozelle, S; Smith, DS; Zhou, CH; Zang, W				Liu, Chengfang; Lu, Louise; Zhang, Linxiu; Bai, Yu; Medina, Alexis; Rozelle, Scott; Smith, Darvin Scott; Zhou, Changhai; Zang, Wei			More Poop, More Precision: Improving Epidemiologic Surveillance of Soil-Transmitted Helminths with Multiple Fecal Sampling using the Kato-Katz Technique	AMERICAN JOURNAL OF TROPICAL MEDICINE AND HYGIENE			English	Article							REPUBLIC-OF-CHINA; STRONGYLOIDES-STERCORALIS; SCHISTOSOMA-JAPONICUM; EGG COUNTS; INFECTIONS; DIAGNOSIS; HOOKWORM; ACCURACY; FLOTAC	Soil-transmitted helminths, or parasitic intestinal worms, are among the most prevalent and geographically widespread parasitic infections in the world. Accurate diagnosis and quantification of helminth infection are critical for informing and assessing deworming interventions. The Kato-Katz thick smear technique, the most widely used laboratory method to quantitatively assess infection prevalence and infection intensity of helminths, has often been compared with other methods. Only a few small-scale studies, however, have considered ways to improve its diagnostic sensitivity. This study, conducted among 4,985 school-age children in an area of rural China with moderate prevalence of helminth infection, examines the effect on diagnostic sensitivity of the Kato-Katz technique when two fecal samples collected over consecutive days are examined and compared with a single sample. A secondary aim was to consider cost-effectiveness by calculating an estimate of the marginal costs of obtaining an additional fecal sample. Our findings show that analysis of an additional fecal sample led to increases of 23%, 26%, and 100% for Ascaris lumbricoides, Trichuris trichiura, and hookworm prevalence, respectively. The cost of collecting a second fecal sample for our study population was approximately USD4.60 per fecal sample. Overall, the findings suggest that investing 31% more capital in fecal sample collection prevents an underestimation of prevalence by about 21%, and hence improves the diagnostic sensitivity of the Kato-Katz method. Especially in areas with light-intensity infections of soil-transmitted helminths and limited public health resources, more accurate epidemiological surveillance using multiple fecal samples will critically inform decisions regarding infection control and prevention.	[Liu, Chengfang] Peking Univ, Sch Adv Agr Sci, China Ctr Agr Policy, Beijing 100871, Peoples R China; [Lu, Louise] Yale Univ, Sch Med, New Haven, CT USA; [Zhang, Linxiu] Chinese Acad Sci, Inst Geog Sci & Nat Resource Res, Ctr Chinese Agr Policy, Beijing, Peoples R China; [Bai, Yu] Shaanxi Normal Univ, Ctr Expt Econ Educ, Xian, Shaanxi, Peoples R China; [Lu, Louise; Medina, Alexis; Rozelle, Scott] Freeman Spogli Inst Int Studies, Rural Educ Action Program, Stanford, CA USA; [Smith, Darvin Scott] Stanford Univ, Sch Med, Stanford, CA 94305 USA; [Zhou, Changhai; Zang, Wei] Chinese Ctr Dis Control & Prevent, Natl Inst Parasit Dis, Shanghai, Peoples R China	Liu, CF (reprint author), Peking Univ, Sch Adv Agr Sci, China Ctr Agr Policy, Beijing 100871, Peoples R China.	cfliu.ccap@pku.edu.cn; louise.lu@yale.edu; lxzhang.ccap@igsnrr.ac.cn; someonebai@gmail.com; amedina5@stanford.edu; rozelle@stanford.edu; dscottsmith@gmail.com; zhouchanghai2005@126.com; zangwei0624@hotmail.com			National Natural Science Foundation of China [71473240, 71333012]; International Initiative for Impact Evaluation (3IE) [PW2.04.02.02]	The authors acknowledge financial support from the National Natural Science Foundation of China (grant numbers 71473240 and 71333012), and the International Initiative for Impact Evaluation (3IE, grant number PW2.04.02.02).		25	0	1	1	4	AMER SOC TROP MED & HYGIENE	MCLEAN	8000 WESTPARK DR, STE 130, MCLEAN, VA 22101 USA	0002-9637	1476-1645		AM J TROP MED HYG	Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg.		2017	97	3					870	875		10.4269/ajtmh.16-0728				6	Public, Environmental & Occupational Health; Tropical Medicine	Public, Environmental & Occupational Health; Tropical Medicine	FT5OM	WOS:000423202900046	28722571				2018-11-10	
