PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Takahashi, R; Kajikawa, Y				Takahashi, Ryohei; Kajikawa, Yuya			Computer-aided diagnosis: A survey with bibliometric analysis	INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MEDICAL INFORMATICS			English	Review						Computer-aided diagnosis; CAD; Citation network analysis; Bibliometric analysi	DECISION-SUPPORT-SYSTEMS; ARTIFICIAL NEURAL-NETWORKS; OPTICAL COHERENCE TOMOGRAPHY; DENTAL PANORAMIC RADIOGRAPHS; PRINCIPAL COMPONENT ANALYSIS; LITERATURE-BASED DISCOVERY; BREAST ULTRASOUND IMAGES; PIGMENTED SKIN-LESIONS; HELICAL CT IMAGES; ALZHEIMERS-DISEASE	Computer-aided diagnosis (CAD) has been a promising area of research over the last two decades. However, CAD is a very complicated subject because it involves a number of medicine and engineering-related fields. To develop a research overview of CAD, we conducted a literature survey with bibliometric analysis, which we report here. Our study determined that CAD research has been classified and categorized according to disease type and imaging modality. This classification began with the CAD of mammograms and eventually progressed to that of brain disease. Furthermore, based on our results, we discuss future directions and opportunities for CAD research. First, in contrast to the typical hypothetical approach, the data-driven approach has shown promise. Second, the normalization of the test datasets and an evaluation method is necessary when adopting an algorithm and a system. Third, we discuss opportunities for the co-evolution of CAD research and imaging instruments-for example, the CAD of bones and pancreatic cancer. Fourth, the potential of synergy with CAD and clinical decision support systems is also discussed. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.	[Takahashi, Ryohei; Kajikawa, Yuya] Tokyo Inst Technol, Sch Environm & Soc, Dept Innovat Sci, Minato Ku, 3-3-6 Shibaura, Tokyo, Japan	Takahashi, R (reprint author), Tokyo Inst Technol, Sch Environm & Soc, Dept Innovat Sci, Minato Ku, 3-3-6 Shibaura, Tokyo, Japan.	takahashi.r.ay@m.titech.ac.jp			Science for RE-designing Science, Technology, and Innovation Policy (SciREX); Research Institute of Science and Technology for Society (RISTEX); Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST)	This research was partially supported by the Science for RE-designing Science, Technology, and Innovation Policy (SciREX), the Research Institute of Science and Technology for Society (RISTEX), and the Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST).		170	10	10	7	28	ELSEVIER IRELAND LTD	CLARE	ELSEVIER HOUSE, BROOKVALE PLAZA, EAST PARK SHANNON, CO, CLARE, 00000, IRELAND	1386-5056	1872-8243		INT J MED INFORM	Int. J. Med. Inform.	MAY	2017	101						58	67		10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2017.02.004				10	Computer Science, Information Systems; Health Care Sciences & Services; Medical Informatics	Computer Science; Health Care Sciences & Services; Medical Informatics	ET6XQ	WOS:000400437200008	28347448				2018-11-10	
