PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Quistian-Vazquez, B; Morales-Cruzado, B; Sarmiento-Gomez, E; Perez-Gutierrez, FG		Jansen, ED; Beier, HT		Quistian-Vazquez, Brenda; Morales-Cruzado, Beatriz; Sarmiento-Gomez, Erick; Perez-Gutierrez, Francisco G. u			Study of the effect of temperature on the optical properties of Latin skins	OPTICAL INTERACTIONS WITH TISSUE AND CELLS XXVIII	Proceedings of SPIE				Conference on Optical Interactions with Tissue and Cells XXVIII	JAN 30-31, 2017	San Francisco, CA	SPIE				Photodynamic therapy (PDT) is a very effective technique for treatment of certain types of cancer, among the most common, skin cancer. PDT requires the presence of three elements: the photosensitizer, light and oxygen. Penetration depth of light into the tumor depends on both the characteristics of the tissue to be treated and the wavelength. As the light dose to be delivered in each lesion depends on the optical properties of the tissue, all the effects that change these properties should be considered in order to choose suitable doses. There are some studies that have determined the maximum dose of radiation tolerated for certain types of skin, but the influence of the temperature on the optical properties, especially for darker skin types, remains unknown. In this study, we analyzed the optical properties of skin in vivo of different latin volunteers in order to study the influence of the temperature on the optical properties and thereby to define more precisely the dose of light to be received by each patient in a personalized way. The optical properties of skin in vivo were investigated using an optical system that included an integrating sphere, a tungsten lamp and a spectrophotometer. Such experimental set up-allowed to obtain spectra reflectance of various volunteers and from this measurement, the absorption coefficient was recovered by Inverse Adding Doubling (IAD) program.					Sarmiento Gomez, Erick/0000-0001-6130-4161												0277-786X		978-1-5106-0565-7; 978-1-5106-0566-4				2017	10062								UNSP 1006210	10.1117/12.2252945								WOS:000406421700021						
