PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Ghadi, A; Mirzanejhad, S				Ghadi, Amin; Mirzanejhad, Saeed			All-optical logic gates using semiconductor-based three-coupled waveguides nonlinear directional coupler	OPTICS COMMUNICATIONS			English	Article						Optical logic devices; Optical nonlinear directional couplers; Two Photon Absorption; Optical waveguides	MACH-ZEHNDER INTERFEROMETER	All-optical logic gates with nonlinear optical (NLO) properties of three-coupled identical waveguides have been proposed and designed theoretically in a unique semiconductor-based symmetric structure. The model uses the NLO interactions of the coupled waveguides, like Kerr effect and Two Photon Absorption (TPA). Unlike the previous studies, we take into account higher order NLO effects of semiconductors such as Free Carriers (FC) and loss to control the switching operation. These NLO phenomena lead to high functionality in a simple unique structure. Therefore, in this work, by setting the input intensity of the waveguides, the logic AND, OR, NAND, and NOR gates are designed in a unique structure with different lengths. Our analysis deals with continuous waves (CW) region and the results are valid for the ranges of short optical pulses with time duration longer than FC life time. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.	[Ghadi, Amin; Mirzanejhad, Saeed] Univ Mazandaran, Fac Basic Sci, Dept Phys, Babol Sar, Iran	Ghadi, A (reprint author), Univ Mazandaran, Fac Basic Sci, Dept Phys, Babol Sar, Iran.	a.ghadi@umz.ac.ir			Iran Telecommunication Research Centre (ITRC)	We acknowledge financial support of Iran Telecommunication Research Centre (ITRC) and greatly appreciate.		28	5	5	1	9	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	0030-4018			OPT COMMUN	Opt. Commun.	JAN 1	2011	284	1					432	435		10.1016/j.optcom.2010.08.020				4	Optics	Optics	702KM	WOS:000285893200076					2018-11-11	
