PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Dong, LW; Wang, H				Dong, L. W.; Wang, H.			Oscillatory behavior of spatial soliton in a gradient refractive index waveguide with nonlocal nonlinearity	APPLIED PHYSICS B-LASERS AND OPTICS			English	Article							LIGHT-BEAM PROPAGATION; INTERFACE; PARTICLE	Oscillatory behavior of spatial solitons in a transverse parabolic gradient refractive index distribution (GRIN) waveguide with both local and nonlocal nonlinearity is investigated. Dynamics of such solitons are analyzed by the effective-particle approach method. For weak nonlocal nonlinearity, solitons oscillate in transverse direction periodically during propagation. The normalized width and maximum of refractive index variation of the waveguide play a key role in determining the oscillating period while the position of soliton oscillatory center is slightly influenced by the nonlocal nonlinearity. Stronger nonlocal nonlinearity leads to instability of the oscillatory solitons. Furthermore, the dynamics of the solitons are simulated numerically and good agreements are obtained between the analysis and numerical results. This behavior may be used in all-optical routers, switches etc.	Zhejiang Normal Univ, Inst Informat Opt, Jinhua 321004, Peoples R China	Dong, LW (reprint author), Zhejiang Normal Univ, Inst Informat Opt, Jinhua 321004, Peoples R China.	donglw@zjnu.cn						25	15	15	0	0	SPRINGER	NEW YORK	233 SPRING ST, NEW YORK, NY 10013 USA	0946-2171	1432-0649		APPL PHYS B-LASERS O	Appl. Phys. B-Lasers Opt.	SEP	2006	84	3					465	469		10.1007/s00340-006-2289-8				5	Optics; Physics, Applied	Optics; Physics	068SH	WOS:000239394200017					2018-11-11	
