PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Wu, YD; Liao, YF; Chen, MH; Chiang, KH		Gong, Q; Cui, YP; Lessard, RA		Wu, YD; Liao, YF; Chen, MH; Chiang, KH			Nonlinear all-optical phase and power-controled switch by using the spatial soliton interaction	Nonlinear Optical Phenomena and Applications	PROCEEDINGS OF THE SOCIETY OF PHOTO-OPTICAL INSTRUMENTATION ENGINEERS (SPIE)		English	Proceedings Paper	Conference on Nonlinear Optical Phenomena and Applications	NOV 08-11, 2004	Beijing, PEOPLES R CHINA	SPIE, Chinese Opt Soc		all-optical switch; nonlinear waveguide; spatial solitons; beam propagation method	WAVE-GUIDE; LOGIC GATES; TE WAVES	We propose a novel nonlinear all-optical switch by using the phase and power modulation of spatial solitons. The proposed waveguide structure is composed of a straight nonlinear signal waveguide, a nonlinear delay branch, a nonlinear control waveguide, and three nonlinear output guides. By properly launching the control power and varying the length of the delay branch, this nonlinear waveguide structure could really function as an all-optical switch. It could be a potential key component in the application of integrated-optics circuits.	Natl Kaohsiung Univ Appl Sci, Kaohsiung, Taiwan	Wu, YD (reprint author), Natl Kaohsiung Univ Appl Sci, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.							25	1	1	0	0	SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING	BELLINGHAM	1000 20TH ST, PO BOX 10, BELLINGHAM, WA 98227-0010 USA	0277-786X		0-8194-5601-2	P SOC PHOTO-OPT INS			2005	5646						334	344		10.1117/12.574123				11	Optics	Optics	BBX87	WOS:000228294200046					2018-11-11	
