PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Nepomnyashchaya, EK; Velichko, EN; Pleshakov, IV; Aksenov, ET; Savchenko, EA			IOP	Nepomnyashchaya, E. K.; Velichko, E. N.; Pleshakov, I. V.; Aksenov, E. T.; Savchenko, E. A.			Investigation of ferrofluid nanostructure by laser light scattering: medical applications	7TH YOUNG RESEARCHER MEETING	Journal of Physics Conference Series				7th Young Researcher Meeting	OCT 24-26, 2016	Ist Nazl Ricerca Metrologica, Torino, ITALY	Anton Paar, CalRef, Crisel Instruments, ID Quantique, LOT Quantum Design, Pfeiffer Vacuum, Sistemi HS, Teledyne Lecroy, Astrophys Observatory Pino Torinese, Ist Nazl Astrofisica	Ist Nazl Ricerca Metrologica			Investigation of ferrofluids nanostructure by the laser light scattering technique is presented. Experimental studies involved measurements of the intensity of the laser radiation scattered by ferrofluid particles in interaction with albumin and under the influence of magnetic field. The effects of the magnitude and duration of the applied magnetic field on the formation of aggregates of magnetic nanoparticles and also the influence of magnetic fluids of different concentrations on blood proteins are considered. The findings may be useful for medical applications.																	1742-6588						2017	841								UNSP 012020	10.1088/1742-6596/841/1/012020								WOS:000413745100020						
