PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Losio, PA; Ristau, S; Mereu, B; Jost, S; Leu, GF; Sinicco, I				Losio, P. A.; Ristau, S.; Mereu, B.; Jost, S.; Leu, G. -F.; Sinicco, I.			Critical concentration of Zinc in amorphous silicon solar cells	SOLAR ENERGY MATERIALS AND SOLAR CELLS												Transparent conductive oxide (TCO) contacts based on zinc oxide (ZnO) are often used in thin film silicon solar cells and ZnO has a lower contamination potential compared to Tin Oxide or Indium-Tin Oxide. However, in this paper the adverse effects of zinc contamination on solar cell performance in large area systems when using non-optimal processes are demonstrated. Controlled contamination experiments were performed; optical emission spectroscopy allowed us to study the Zn release dynamic; secondary ions mass spectroscopy measurements allowed us to determine the Zn contamination threshold level in a-Si:H solar cells of 10(18) at/cm(3). Higher Zn concentrations lead to loss of cell performance in the initial state and increased light induced degradation compared to cells with lower contamination. Additionally, a simple approach for Zn contamination removal is presented. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.																	0927-0248	1879-3398				DEC	2015	143						488	493		10.1016/j.solmat.2015.08.003								WOS:000364250200064						
