PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Sudduth, KA; Jang, GS; Lerch, RN; Sadler, EJ				Sudduth, Kenneth A.; Jang, Gab-Sue; Lerch, Robert N.; Sadler, E. John			Long-Term Agroecosystem Research in the Central Mississippi River Basin: Hyperspectral Remote Sensing of Reservoir Water Quality	JOURNAL OF ENVIRONMENTAL QUALITY			English	Article							TURBID PRODUCTIVE WATERS; CHLOROPHYLL-A CONCENTRATION; ALGAL-CHLOROPHYLL; SUSPENDED SEDIMENTS; SURFACE WATERS; REFLECTANCE; MODEL; NONDETECTS; DEPTH; LAKE	In situ methods for estimating water quality parameters would facilitate efforts in spatial and temporal monitoring, and optical reflectance sensing has shown potential in this regard, particularly for chlorophyll, suspended sediment, and turbidity. The objective of this research was to develop and evaluate relationships between hyperspectral remote sensing and lake water quality parameters-chlorophyll, turbidity, and N and P species. Proximal hyperspectral water reflectance data were obtained on seven sampling dates for multiple arms of Mark Twain Lake, a large man-made reservoir in northeastern Missouri. Aerial hyperspectral data were also obtained on two dates. Water samples were collected and analyzed in the laboratory for chlorophyll, nutrients, and turbidity. Previously reported reflectance indices and full-spectrum (i.e., partial least squares regression) methods were used to develop relationships between spectral and water quality data. With the exception of dissolved NH3, all measured water quality parameters were strongly related (R-2 >= 0.7) to proximal reflectance across all measurement dates. Aerial hyperspectral sensing was somewhat less accurate than proximal sensing for the two measurement dates where both were obtained. Although full-spectrum calibrations were more accurate for chlorophyll and turbidity than results from previously reported models, those previous models performed better for an independent test set. Because extrapolation of estimation models to dates other than those used to calibrate the model greatly increased estimation error for some parameters, collection of calibration samples at each sensing date would be required for the most accurate remote sensing estimates of water quality.	[Sudduth, Kenneth A.; Lerch, Robert N.; Sadler, E. John] ARS, USDA, Cropping Syst & Water Qual Res Unit, Columbia, MO 65211 USA; [Jang, Gab-Sue] Yeungnam Univ, Dept Life Sci, Gyongsan, South Korea	Sudduth, KA (reprint author), ARS, USDA, Cropping Syst & Water Qual Res Unit, 269 Agr Engn Bldg, Columbia, MO 65211 USA.	Ken.Sudduth@ars.usda.gov		Sadler, Edward/0000-0003-3524-8340; Sudduth, Kenneth/0000-0002-2558-0668				36	4	4	1	35	AMER SOC AGRONOMY	MADISON	677 S SEGOE RD, MADISON, WI 53711 USA	0047-2425	1537-2537		J ENVIRON QUAL	J. Environ. Qual.	JAN-FEB	2015	44	1					71	83		10.2134/jeq2014.02.0060				13	Environmental Sciences	Environmental Sciences & Ecology	AY8YH	WOS:000347836100009	25602322				2018-11-11	
