PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Schon, B			IEEE	Schon, Balint			Developing performance of waste water source heat pump systems by heat transport investigation	2017 6TH INTERNATIONAL YOUTH CONFERENCE ON ENERGY (IYCE)					6th International Youth Conference on Energy (IYCE)	JUN 21-24, 2017	Budapest, HUNGARY					The share of the building sector in developed countries accounts for 30-40% of the total energy consumption. Space heating and cooling and domestic hot water supply represent the biggest share in energy consumed. Despite its low enthalpy content, sewage water - what is seen as a renewable resource could represent an interesting source for energy especially when heat pumps are applied. In the early 1980s, waste (sewage) water source heat pumps (WWSHPs) were widely applied in Sweden and Norway and partially applied in China. Due to the technical development (heat exchangers and heat pumps) and strengthening of environmental considerations in the past two decades, it has become increasingly popular. The heat pump part of the construction does not vary widely but the utilization rate mostly depends on the evolution and design of the heat exchanger side. First, a brief review of wastewater heat exchangers and construction applications is presented. This is followed by a demonstration of Hungarian-developed Thermowatt technology. To make this technology - which utilizes the great potential of densely populated cities - economically feasible, we need to increase the efficiency to minimize the payback period due by the lower operation cost. In this study, the heat transport process is investigated, which is the key element of the system's efficiency. The aim of my study is to improve the technology and increase the system efficiency. By clarifying the complex physical and biological method, biofilm creating and developing, there is opportunity to prevent the emergence of biofilm. The literature research, the measurement in laboratory and the collected information about the operating system shows the magnitude of different physical parameters, and other circumstances. It is concluded that from the two negative effects, physical fouling is stronger than the biofilm created on the inner surface of heat exchanger tubes, but the latter should not be neglected. Finally, different suggestions were listed at both areas to eliminate or weaken these influences. Thanks to these, the amount of heat that is transported is increased and ultimately less electricity is needed.																			978-1-5090-6409-0				2017																		WOS:000425930300003						
