PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Upadhyay, G; Saxena, R; Joshi, G		Elangovan, S		Upadhyay, Garvita; Saxena, Rachit; Joshi, Gaurav			Optimal Capacitor Placement and Sizing in Distribution System Using Hybrid Approach of PSO-GA	PROCEEDINGS OF 2017 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ADVANCES IN ELECTRICAL TECHNOLOGY FOR GREEN ENERGY (ICAETGT)			English	Proceedings Paper	IEEE International Conference on Advances in Electrical Technology for Green Energy (ICAETGT)	SEP 23, 2017	Coimbatore, INDIA	IEEE		Distributed Power station; Newton Raphson; Capacitor Placement; Power Loss		A distributed system is referred as an interface among bulky power system and consumers. In such distributed systems the voltage of the power grid is decreased when it moves at far from substations. Other problems are loss of power during transmission, variable voltage profile, increasing cost of system etc. Capacitors are used for performance enhancement of the system. Because all of these factors or problems directly affected by performance or energy efficiency of the system. There are various methods which are used for optimal placement of the capacitors in distributed power system. In this work the hybrid approach which combines two techniques such as GA and State transition have been developed in order to achieve the energy efficient distributed system. The result section proves the performance of proposed work by comparing the various techniques with proposed work.	[Upadhyay, Garvita; Saxena, Rachit] Rajasthan Coll Engn Women, Dept Elect Engn, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India; [Joshi, Gaurav] Dept Elect & Commun Engn, Delhi, India	Upadhyay, G (reprint author), Rajasthan Coll Engn Women, Dept Elect Engn, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India.	garvita.up@gmail.com						23	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA			978-1-5386-2138-7				2017							1	6						6	GREEN & SUSTAINABLE SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY; Energy & Fuels; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Science & Technology - Other Topics; Energy & Fuels; Engineering	BK1WD	WOS:000432325500001					2018-11-11	
