PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Lucache, DD; Moisa, C; Lobry, J			IEEE	Lucache, Dorin D.; Moisa, Cristina; Lobry, Jacques			Economic Apraisal of Optimal Location and Sizing of Capacitors in Radial Distribution Systems Using PSO	2014 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON APPLIED AND THEORETICAL ELECTRICITY (ICATE)	International Conference on Applied and Theoretical Electricity		English	Proceedings Paper	International Conference on Applied and Theoretical Electricity (ICATE)	OCT 23-25, 2014	Craiova, ROMANIA	Univ Craiova, Fac Elect Engn, Inst Elect & Elect Engineers, IEEE Romania Sect, IEEE Romanian Chapter EMB Soc, IEEE Romanian Chapter EMC Soc, IEEE Romanian Chapter MAG Soc, IEEE Romanian Chapter PE Soc, Minist Natl Educ, Assoc Support Engn Educ		capacitors; distribution system; particle swarm optimization; economic profitability		The principal roles of capacitors in power systems are to supply reactive power to minimize loss and to improve the voltage profile. The optimization problem has to find the appropriate placement of capacitors that lead both to minimal system power losses and minimal total capacitor costs. This problem is largely presented in literature and is commonly solved using heuristic optimization techniques. However, the project profitability depends on prices and economical context. In this paper, a project economical appraisal was combined with the particle swarm optimization (PSO) technique in order to assess the profitability of the optimal capacitor installation in a 33-bus distribution network. A comparison between two objective functions and different locations numbers to install capacitor banks has been done.	[Lucache, Dorin D.; Moisa, Cristina] Gheorghe Asachi Tech Univ Iasi, Fac Elect Engn, Iasi, Romania; [Lobry, Jacques] Univ Mons, Polytech Fac, Dept Elect Engn, B-7000 Mons, Belgium	Lucache, DD (reprint author), Gheorghe Asachi Tech Univ Iasi, Fac Elect Engn, Iasi, Romania.	lukake@tuiasi.ro; cristina.m.moisa@gmail.com; Jacques.Lobry@umons.ac.be	LUCACHE, Dorin Dumitru/A-4746-2018	LUCACHE, Dorin Dumitru/0000-0002-6060-117X				15	0	0	0	0	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2376-4163		978-1-4799-4161-2	INT CONF APPL THEOR			2014														6	Engineering, Electrical & Electronic	Engineering	BC4MW	WOS:000352737400038					2018-11-11	
