PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Kogo, B; Wang, B; Wrobel, L; Chizari, M		Crane, R; Hojo, K; Xu, SX; Cipolla, RC		Kogo, Bridget; Wang, Bin; Wrobel, Luiz; Chizari, Mahmoud			THERMAL ANALYSIS OF GIRTH WELDED JOINTS OF DISSIMILAR METALS IN PIPES WITH VARYING CLAD THICKNESSES	PROCEEDINGS OF THE ASME PRESSURE VESSELS AND PIPING CONFERENCE, 2017, VOL 1B					ASME Pressure Vessels and Piping Conference	JUL 16-20, 2017	Waikoloa, HI	ASME, Pressure Vessels & Pip Div				Thermal analyses of girth welded joints of dads have been carried out using 2D and 3D finite element analysis (FEA) by using the engineering software Abaqus v.2016 (Dassault Systemes). Transient temperature curves have been generated for different cladding thicknesses (of stainless steel and mild steel). The welding of the two dissimilar materials has been carried out in-house with the aid of a Tungsten Arc weld with dynamic measurement of the temperature profile in the vicinity areas of the welding track using high temperature thermocouples. Comparison of the measured-temperature versus the simulation results shows close agreement.																			978-0-7918-5791-5				2017									V01BT01A066									WOS:000422810400066						
