PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Mlakic, D; Nikolovski, S		Biljanovic, P; Butkovic, Z; Skala, K; Grbac, TG; CicinSain, M; Sruk, V; Ribaric, S; Gros, S; Vrdoljak, B; Mauher, M; Tijan, E; Lukman, D		Mlakic, Dragan; Nikolovski, Srete			Anfis as a Method for Determinating MPPT in the Photovoltaic System Simulated in Matlab/Simulink	2016 39TH INTERNATIONAL CONVENTION ON INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY, ELECTRONICS AND MICROELECTRONICS (MIPRO)					39th International Convention on Information and Communication Technology, Electronics and Microelectronics (MIPRO)	MAY 30-JUN 03, 2016	Opatija, CROATIA	MIPRO Croatian Soc, IEEE Region 8, Republ Croatia, Minist Sci Educ & Sports, Republ Croatia, Minist Maritime Affairs, Transport & Infrastructure, Republ Croatia, Minist Entrepreneurship & Crafts, Republ Croatia, Minist Public Adm, Croatian Chamber Economy, Univ Rijeka, Univ Zagreb, IEEE Croatia Sect, IEEE Croatia Sect Comp Chapter, IEEE Croatia Sect Electron Devices Solid State Circuits Joint Chapter, IEEE Croatia Sect Educ Chapter, IEEE Croatia Sect Commun Chapter, T Croatian Telecom, Ericsson Nikola Tesla, Koncar Elect Ind, HEP Croatian Elect Co, VIPnet, Univ Zagreb, Fac Elect Engn & Comp, Rudjer Boskovic Inst, Univ Rijeka, Fac Maritime Studies, Univ Rijeka, Fac Engn, Univ Rijeka, Fac Econ, Univ Zagreb, Fac Org & Informat, Univ Rijeka, Fac Tourism & Hospital Management, Polytechn Zagreb, EuroCloud Croatia, Croatian Regulatory Author Network Ind, Croatian Post, Erste&Steiermarkische bank, Selmet, CISEx, Kermas energija, Rezultanta, River Publishers, InfoDom, Hewlett Packard Croatia, IN2, Transmitters & Commun Co, Storm Comp, Nokia, King ICT, Microsoft Croatia, Micro Link, Mjerne tehnologije, Altpro, Danieli Automat, ib proCADD, Nomen				Photovoltaic systems as part of larger distribution systems for the production of electricity have non-linear current-voltage characteristics. These characteristics depend on the temperature of the solar cells and insolation of panels. The method for the search of the maximum power or MPPT is widely known, and there are many offered algorithm solutions. The aim of this paper is to present ANFIS (Adaptive Neural Fuzzy System Inference) as a method of computer intelligence in the search function of maximum power or maximum utilization of the PV system, without prior knowledge of the system. MPPT ANFIS will be located between the PV panels and devices for voltage regulation. Inputs used to go inside the fuzzy regulators and outputs of the fuzzy regulators are going into power changing device. The advantage of this method is the low cost of implementation because it uses embedded computer systems and does not require additional sensors for measuring temperature and insolation. It is very easy to upgrade in the case of increasing the knowledge base used in FIS membership function. Everything is simulated by MATLAB/Simulink software on the one-phase IBC system.					Nikolovski, Srete/0000-0002-9033-4332; Mlakic, Dragan/0000-0001-7258-2861														978-953-233-088-5				2016							1082	1086										WOS:000391360600172						
