PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Arroyo-Martinez, PC; Sanchez-Flores, NA; Villafuerte-Castrejon, ME; Vivar-Ocampo, R				Arroyo-Martinez, Paula C.; Sanchez-Flores, Norma A.; Villafuerte-Castrejon, Maria E.; Vivar-Ocampo, Rodrigo			Synergistic Effect of 4A Zeolite from Rice Husk Ash without Aging Time and Silane on the Adhesion Properties of a Warm Mix Asphalt	JOURNAL OF THE BRAZILIAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY												4A Zeolite was synthesized using rice husk ash (RHA) as a raw material in a microwave-assisted hydrothermal synthesis. Two new procedures were proposed: procedure A, using RHA as the raw material, and procedure B, using the depolymerized RHA. Both procedures were performed using microwave-assisted hydrothermal synthesis, and neither synthesis required an aging time. Crystallinities of over 90 and 80% were reached at 100 degrees C after 30 min of microwave heating for procedures A and B, respectively. The obtained zeolites were used as warm mix asphalt additives, and the performance of the zeolite obtained from procedure A was better. Additionally, the zeolite obtained from procedure A and commercial silane were used separately as asphalt-aggregate adhesion promoter. An increase in the adhesion percentage from 30% of a blank sample to 94% was observed.																	0103-5053	1678-4790				JAN	2018	29	1					58	66		10.21577/0103-5053.20170112								WOS:000414146700008						
