PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Highland, F; Hart, C		Dagli, CH		Highland, Fred; Hart, Corey			Implementing Multilayer Neural Network Behavior Using Polychronous Wavefront Computation	COMPLEX ADAPTIVE SYSTEMS	Procedia Computer Science		English	Proceedings Paper	Conference on Engineering Cyber Physical Systems: Applying Theory to Practice	NOV 02-04, 2016	Los Angeles, CA	Missouri Univ Sci & Technol		polychronous wavefront computation; multilayer perceptrons; spiking neural networks		Polychronous Wavefront Computation (PWC) is an abstraction of spiking neural networks that provides a potentially practical model for implementing neuromorphic computing systems. While it's has been shown to exhibit some basic computational capabilities, its use in complex neuro-computational models remains to be explored. The paper presents a model and approach for configuring PWC transponders to implement multilayer neural network behavior to provide a basis for more complex applications of the technology. The model uses a set of input transponders representing pattern features to stimulate hidden layer transponders that combine features and trigger output layer transponders to identify patterns. The input layer transponder geometry is selected to create wavefront intersections for all relevant feature combinations. Hidden layer transponders are positioned by solving the intersection of the circles equations defined by sets of input transponders. Output layer transponders are defined to collect complete sets of features for recognition based on the hidden layer transponder geometry. The approach uses the intersections of three wavefronts to maximize transponder selectivity and increase information density. The concept is experimentally demonstrated and analyzed with a 7-segment display digit recognition application which provides a simple but representative example of more complex pattern recognition problems. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.	[Highland, Fred] Univ Maryland Baltimore Cty, Baltimore, MD 21228 USA; [Hart, Corey] nNetworx LLC, Philadelphia, PA USA		fred.highland.mobile@gmail.com						12	0	0	0	1	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	SARA BURGERHARTSTRAAT 25, PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	1877-0509			PROCEDIA COMPUT SCI			2016	95						159	167		10.1016/j.procs.2016.09.307				9	Computer Science, Hardware & Architecture; Computer Science, Interdisciplinary Applications; Computer Science, Theory & Methods	Computer Science	BG8TL	WOS:000392696000020		Other Gold			2018-11-12	
