PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Highland, F; Hart, C		Dagli, CH		Highland, Fred; Hart, Corey			Unsupervised Learning of Patterns Using Multilayer Reverberating Configurations of Polychronous Wavefront Computation	COMPLEX ADAPTIVE SYSTEMS	Procedia Computer Science		English	Proceedings Paper	Conference on Engineering Cyber Physical Systems: Applying Theory to Practice	NOV 02-04, 2016	Los Angeles, CA	Missouri Univ Sci & Technol		polychronous wavefront computation; pattern recognition; multilayer neural networks; spiking neural networks; unsupervised learning		Polychronous Wavefront Computation (PWC) is an abstraction of spiking neural networks that has been shown to be capable of basic computational functions and simple pattern recognition through multilayer configurations. The objective of this work is to apply unsupervised learning methods to multilayer PWC configurations to improve performance providing a basis for more advanced applications and deep learning. Previous work on defining multilayer PWC configurations is extended by applying biologically inspired learning methods to dynamically suppress unneeded transponders and improve configuration performance. Simple learning approaches based on concepts from spike-timing-dependent plasticity and potentiation decay models are adapted to PWC transponders and combined with training sequences to optimize the transponder configurations for recognition. Learning is further enhanced by configuring transponders in recurrent structures to activate hidden layer transponders creating reverberations that reinforce learning. A means to classify multiple input patterns into general concepts is also introduced to further enhance the recognition capabilities of the configurations. The concepts are experimentally validated and analyzed through application to a 7-segment display digit recognition problem showing that the approach can improve PWC configuration performance and reduce complexity. (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.	[Highland, Fred] Univ Maryland Baltimore Cty, Baltimore, MD 21228 USA; NNetworx LLC, Philadelphia, PA USA		fred.highland.mobile@gmail.com						13	0	0	0	0	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	SARA BURGERHARTSTRAAT 25, PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	1877-0509			PROCEDIA COMPUT SCI			2016	95						175	184		10.1016/j.procs.2016.09.310				10	Computer Science, Hardware & Architecture; Computer Science, Interdisciplinary Applications; Computer Science, Theory & Methods	Computer Science	BG8TL	WOS:000392696000022		Other Gold			2018-11-12	
