PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Doorwar, M; Malathi, P			IEEE	Doorwar, Minaxi; Malathi, P.			COMPARATIVE ANALYSIS OF DIFFERENT ARCITECTURE BASED PROTOCOL IN WIRELESS MULTIMEDIA SENSOR NETWORK	2017 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON EMERGING TRENDS & INNOVATION IN ICT (ICEI)					International Conference on Emerging Trends & Innovation in ICT (ICEI)	FEB 03-05, 2017	Pune Inst Comp Technol, Pune, INDIA		Pune Inst Comp Technol			The modern improvement in technology and wireless sensor network, emerge the use of wireless multimedia sensor network in different applications. In WMSNs, different architecture based routing has been refocusing area of research. Wireless multimedia sensor network (WMSN) consist of a multimedia sensor, whose have a capability to capture the audio, video, image and scalar data for different application like environment monitoring, traffic monitoring, healthcare, and military. The main object of paper is to analyze the performance of the various protocols on the basis of different architecture with QoS parameters like reliability delay, bandwidth optimization and efficiency of energy is depending on the path selection, architecture, type of data and resource utilization. This paper surveys the various existing routing protocol performance parameters and design challenge for WMSN routing techniques. In addition, open research issue with future research trends.																			978-1-5090-3404-8				2017							92	97										WOS:000425243100018						
