PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
B	Hegde, AR; Meenakshi, T; Kumar, NA; Pai, MV		Elangovan, S		Hegde, Akshatha. R.; Meenakshi, T.; Kumar, Arun N.; Pai, M. Vishwanath			Power Factor Correction of Four Switch BLDC Motor Drive Using Bridgeless-CSC Converter	PROCEEDINGS OF 2017 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ADVANCES IN ELECTRICAL TECHNOLOGY FOR GREEN ENERGY (ICAETGT)					IEEE International Conference on Advances in Electrical Technology for Green Energy (ICAETGT)	SEP 23, 2017	Coimbatore, INDIA	IEEE				A performance comparison of Bridgeless-CSC converter with the diode bridge rectifier is proposed in this paper. The diode bridge rectifier is generally used to convert ac to dc. The power factor can be improved by employing the LC filter. The harmonic distortion in the supply is high reducing the power quality. But when these performance is of major concern, the Bridgeless-CSC converter can be implemented which improves those parameters. The output from proposed converter is fed to the BLDC motor. The BLDC motor with four switch reduces the switching losses. The BL-CSC converter has two switches in which one conducts at each half cycle reducing the conduction losses.																			978-1-5386-2138-7				2017							56	63										WOS:000432325500011						
