PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Flanagan, K; Fallon, E; Awad, A; Connolly, P			IEEE	Flanagan, Kieran; Fallon, Enda; Awad, Abir; Connolly, Paul			Self-Configuring NetFlow Anomaly Detection using Cluster Density Analysis	2017 19TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ADVANCED COMMUNICATIONS TECHNOLOGY (ICACT) - OPENING NEW ERA OF SMART SOCIETY	International Conference on Advanced Communication Technology		English	Proceedings Paper	19th International Conference on Advanced Communication Technology (ICACT)	FEB 19-22, 2017	Pyeongchang, SOUTH KOREA	Global IT Res Inst, IEEE Commun Soc, Natl Informat Soc Agcy, Elect & Telecommunicat Res Inst, Gangwon Convent & Visitors Bur, Korean Inst Commun Sci, IEEK Commun Soc, Korean Inst Informat Scientists & Engineers, Open Stand & Internet Assoc, Korea Inst Informat Secur & Crytol		Anomaly Detection; NetFlow; Clustering; Density Analysis		The growing number of malicious network attacks has resulted in the need for a fast, reliable method to identify possible malicious activity. For any organization, it is critical that confidential and proprietary data is sufficiently secured to address both legal and contractual obligations. The changing nature of security attacks has caused a surge of interest in anomaly detection mechanisms. Such mechanisms are suitable as they can dynamically adapt to changed network conditions and threats without security personnel intervention. While anomaly detection mechanisms have significant potential, they are technically limited. Many anomaly detection approaches are unsuitable for real time environments. The approaches also typically operate based on "what is common is normal". Mechanisms are typically singular in focus analysing data on one specific type. This paper proposes a novel framework to detect anomalies previously hidden within current detection techniques. The approach is easily extensible taking input from many security assessment applications; network traffic, asset criticality. Using time based correlations with historic data; a method for generating a normalized view of activity on the network is achieved. Once normality has been established for specific time intervals an extensible environment is implemented which allows for the active monitoring of anomalies in real-time. Anomalies which had sufficient "commonality" to remain undetected by other mechanisms are identified and analysed. The proposed solution is completely autonomous, capable of acting independently with no previous knowledge required. The presented results describe NetFlow activity of the NPD Groups' network over a 24-hour period and outline real world anomalies that were detected.	[Flanagan, Kieran; Fallon, Enda] Athlone Inst Technol, Software Res Inst, Athlone, Ireland; [Awad, Abir] Univ South Wales, Fac Comp Engn & Sci, Pontypridd, M Glam, Wales; [Flanagan, Kieran; Connolly, Paul] NPD Grp Inc, IDA Business Pk, Athlone, Westmeath, Ireland	Flanagan, K (reprint author), Athlone Inst Technol, Software Res Inst, Athlone, Ireland.; Flanagan, K (reprint author), NPD Grp Inc, IDA Business Pk, Athlone, Westmeath, Ireland.	k.flanagan@research.ait.ie; efallon@ait.ie; abir.awad@southwalse.ac.uk; paul.connolly@npd.com						23	0	0	0	1	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	1738-9445		978-8-9968-6509-4	INT CONF ADV COMMUN			2017							421	427						7	Computer Science, Theory & Methods; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic; Telecommunications	Computer Science; Engineering; Telecommunications	BH8BP	WOS:000403150000080					2018-11-12	
