PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Reyes-Castro, PA; Harris, RB; Brown, HE; Christopherson, GL; Ernst, KC				Reyes-Castro, Pablo A.; Harris, Robin B.; Brown, Heidi E.; Christopherson, Gary L.; Ernst, Kacey C.			Spatio-temporal and neighborhood characteristics of two dengue outbreaks in two arid cities of Mexico	ACTA TROPICA												Little is currently known about the spatial-temporal dynamics of dengue epidemics in arid areas. This study assesses dengue outbreaks that occurred in two arid cities of Mexico, Hermosillo and Navojoa, located in northern state of Sonora. Laboratory confirmed dengue cases from Hermosillo (N = 2730) and Navojoa (N = 493) were geocoded by residence and assigned neighborhood-level characteristics from the 2010 Mexican census. Kernel density and Space-time cluster analysis was performed to detect high density areas and space-time clusters of dengue. Ordinary Least Square regression was used to assess the changing socioeconomic characteristics of cases over the course of the outbreaks. Both cities exhibited contiguous patterns of space-time clustering. Initial areas of dissemination were characterized in both cities by high population density, high percentage of occupied houses, and lack of healthcare. Future research and control efforts in these regions should consider these space-time and socioeconomic patterns. (C) 2017 Published by Elsevier B.V.					Brown, Heidi/0000-0001-8578-5510												0001-706X	1873-6254				MAR	2017	167						174	182		10.1016/j.actatropica.2017.01.001								WOS:000394071300024	28062233					
