PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Puri, A; Sivaraman, A; Zhang, W; Clark, MR; Banga, AK				Puri, Ashana; Sivaraman, Arunprasad; Zhang, Wei; Clark, Meredith R.; Banga, Ajay K.			Expanding the Domain of Drug Delivery for HIV Prevention: Exploration of the Transdermal Route	CRITICAL REVIEWS IN THERAPEUTIC DRUG CARRIER SYSTEMS			English	Review						HIV prevention; pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP); transdermal delivery; chemical penetration enhancers; physical enhancement techniques	MEDIATED INTRADERMAL DELIVERY; ANTIRETROVIRAL PREEXPOSURE PROPHYLAXIS; TENOFOVIR DISOPROXIL FUMARATE; ELASTIC LIPOSOMAL FORMULATION; TERAMEPROCOL VAGINAL OINTMENT; SKIN PERMEATION; IN-VITRO; PENETRATION ENHANCERS; STRATUM-CORNEUM; IMMUNODEFICIENCY-VIRUS	Constant efforts for HIV prevention using antiretroviral drugs, pre- and post-exposure prophylactic agents, and microbicides tire being made by researchers. Drug-delivery systems such as oral tablets and coitally dependent vaginal gels are short acting, require daily application, and are associated with user adherence issues, whereas the coitally independent systems such as injectables and biodegradable implants are long acting, lasting several months, during which time the termination of prophylaxis is impractical in case of adverse effects. An effective drug-delivery system to be used for an intermediate duration, if available, would be an attractive alternative option for users in terms of adherence. Transdermal delivery systems, overcoming most of the limitations of the other routes of administration and aiming to provide sustained delivery of drugs through skin, may be explored for HIV prevention. Passive and physical enhancement techniques may be designed strategically to improve the transdermal delivery of HIV preventive agents.	[Puri, Ashana; Sivaraman, Arunprasad; Banga, Ajay K.] Mercer Univ, Coll Pharm, Dept Pharmaceut Sci, 3001 Mercer Univ Dr, Atlanta, GA 30341 USA; [Zhang, Wei; Clark, Meredith R.] Eastern Virginia Med Sch, Dept Obstet & Gynecol, CONRAD, Arlington, VA USA	Banga, AK (reprint author), Mercer Univ, Coll Pharm, Dept Pharmaceut Sci, 3001 Mercer Univ Dr, Atlanta, GA 30341 USA.	Banga_ak@mercer.edu			United States Agency for International Development (USAID) [MAPS2-15-061, AID-OAA-A-14-00010]	This work is made possible by the generous support of the American people through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) under an Agreement (MAPS2-15-061) under a Cooperative Agreement (AID-OAA-A-14-00010) to CONRAD, Eastern Virginia Medical School. The views expressed by the authors do not necessarily reflect the view's of USAID.		176	1	1	0	0	BEGELL HOUSE INC	DANBURY	50 NORTH ST, DANBURY, CT 06810 USA	0743-4863	2162-660X		CRIT REV THER DRUG	Crit. Rev. Ther. Drug Carr. Syst.		2017	34	6					551	587		10.1615/CritRevTherDrugCarrierSyst.2017020147				37	Pharmacology & Pharmacy	Pharmacology & Pharmacy	FQ1ES	WOS:000418099700003	29256837				2018-11-12	
