PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Ita, K				Ita, Kevin			Transdermal Delivery of Drugs with Microneedles-Potential and Challenges	PHARMACEUTICS			English	Review						transdermal; microneedles; drug delivery; dissolving microneedles; hydrogel-forming microneedles		Transdermal drug delivery offers a number of advantages including improved patient compliance, sustained release, avoidance of gastric irritation, as well as elimination of pre-systemic first-pass effect. However, only few medications can be delivered through the transdermal route in therapeutic amounts. Microneedles can be used to enhance transdermal drug delivery. In this review, different types of microneedles are described and their methods of fabrication highlighted. Microneedles can be fabricated in different forms: hollow, solid, and dissolving. There are also hydrogel-forming microneedles. A special attention is paid to hydrogel-forming microneedles. These are innovative microneedles which do not contain drugs but imbibe interstitial fluid to form continuous conduits between dermal microcirculation and an attached patch-type reservoir. Several microneedles approved by regulatory authorities for clinical use are also examined. The last part of this review discusses concerns and challenges regarding microneedle use.	[Ita, Kevin] Touro Univ, Coll Pharm, Mare Isl Vallejo, CA 94592 USA	Ita, K (reprint author), Touro Univ, Coll Pharm, Mare Isl Vallejo, CA 94592 USA.	kevin.ita@tu.edu						53	52	52	10	47	MDPI AG	BASEL	ST ALBAN-ANLAGE 66, CH-4052 BASEL, SWITZERLAND	1999-4923			PHARMACEUTICS	Pharmaceutics	SEP	2015	7	3					90	105		10.3390/pharmaceutics7030090				16	Pharmacology & Pharmacy	Pharmacology & Pharmacy	VB8JQ	WOS:000418789700001	26131647	DOAJ Gold, Green Published			2018-11-12	
