PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Meng, D; Cao, GT; Duan, Y; Zhu, MH; Tu, LP; Xu, D; Xu, JT				Meng, Dan; Cao, Guitao; Duan, Ye; Zhu, Minghua; Tu, Liping; Xu, Dong; Xu, Jiatuo			Tongue Images Classification Based on Constrained High Dispersal Network	EVIDENCE-BASED COMPLEMENTARY AND ALTERNATIVE MEDICINE			English	Article							SCALE	Computer aided tongue diagnosis has a great potential to play important roles in traditional Chinese medicine (TCM). However, the majority of the existing tongue image analyses and classification methods are based on the low-level features, which may not provide a holistic view of the tongue. Inspired by deep convolutional neural network (CNN), we propose a novel feature extraction framework called constrained high dispersal neural networks (CHDNet) to extract unbiased features and reduce human labor for tongue diagnosis in TCM. Previous CNN models have mostly focused on learning convolutional filters and adapting weights between them, but these models have two major issues: redundancy and insufficient capability in handling unbalanced sample distribution. We introduce high dispersal and local response normalization operation to address the issue of redundancy. We also add multiscale feature analysis to avoid the problem of sensitivity to deformation. Our proposed CHDNet learns high-level features and provides more classification information during training time, which may result in higher accuracy when predicting testing samples. We tested the proposed method on a set of 267 gastritis patients and a control group of 48 healthy volunteers. Test results show that CHDNet is a promising method in tongue image classification for the TCM study.	[Meng, Dan; Cao, Guitao; Zhu, Minghua] East China Normal Univ, MOE Res Ctr Software Hardware Codesign Engn, Shanghai 200062, Peoples R China; [Cao, Guitao; Duan, Ye; Tu, Liping; Xu, Dong] Univ Missouri, Dept Comp Sci, Columbia, MO 65211 USA; [Tu, Liping] Shanghai Univ TCM, Dept TCM Informat & Technol Ctr, Shanghai, Peoples R China; [Xu, Jiatuo] Shanghai Univ Tradit Chinese Med, Dept Basic Med Coll, 1200 Cailun Rd, Shanghai 201203, Peoples R China	Cao, GT; Zhu, MH (reprint author), East China Normal Univ, MOE Res Ctr Software Hardware Codesign Engn, Shanghai 200062, Peoples R China.; Cao, GT (reprint author), Univ Missouri, Dept Comp Sci, Columbia, MO 65211 USA.	gtcao@sei.ecnu.edu.cn; mhzhu@sei.ecnu.edu.cn			NSFC-Zhejiang Joint Fund for the Integration of Industrialization and Informatization [U1609220]; National Natural Science Foundation of China [61375015, 81373556, 61572061]	This work was supported in part by the NSFC-Zhejiang Joint Fund for the Integration of Industrialization and Informatization under Grant no. U1609220, and it was supported in part by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant no. 61375015, Grant no. 81373556, and Grant no. 61572061). The authors would like to thank Professor Shao Li for providing the data.		33	1	1	3	11	HINDAWI LTD	LONDON	ADAM HOUSE, 3RD FLR, 1 FITZROY SQ, LONDON, W1T 5HF, ENGLAND	1741-427X	1741-4288		EVID-BASED COMPL ALT	Evid.-based Complement Altern. Med.		2017									7452427	10.1155/2017/7452427				12	Integrative & Complementary Medicine	Integrative & Complementary Medicine	ER1LZ	WOS:000398553900001	28465706	DOAJ Gold, Green Published			2018-12-10	
