PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Zhang, S; Lei, MJ; Dong, YT; He, W				Zhang, Shuang; Lei, Minjie; Dong, Yiting; He, Wei			Adaptive neural network control of coordinated robotic manipulators with output constraint	IET CONTROL THEORY AND APPLICATIONS			English	Article						adaptive control; neurocontrollers; manipulators; uncertainty handling; stability; control system synthesis; radial basis function networks; function approximation; Lyapunov methods; closed loop systems; adaptive neural network control; coordinated robotic manipulators; output constraint; tracking control problem; uncertainty handling; instability handling; controller design; radial basis function neural network; bounded function approximation; continuous function approximation; barrier Lyapunov function; stability analysis; closed-loop system	PARTICLE SWARM OPTIMIZATION; CONTROL SCHEME; FUZZY CONTROL; SYSTEMS; INPUT; APPROXIMATION	In this study, the authors aim to solve the tracking control problem of coordinated robotic manipulators. In order to handle with the uncertainties and instability of coordinated robotic manipulators and improve the performance of the system with output constraint, they design a controller by using radial basis function neural network which has the ability to approximate any bounded and continuous functions effectively. A barrier Lyapunov function is also introduced to prevent the violation of output constraint. The stability analysis of the closed-loop system is provided and the performance of the controller is verified through simulation.	[Zhang, Shuang] Univ Elect Sci & Technol China, Sch Aeronaut & Astronaut, Chengdu 611731, Peoples R China; [Lei, Minjie; Dong, Yiting] Univ Elect Sci & Technol China, Ctr Robot & Sch Automat Engn, Chengdu 611731, Peoples R China; [He, Wei] Univ Sci & Technol Beijing, Sch Automat & Elect Engn, Beijing 100083, Peoples R China	He, W (reprint author), Univ Sci & Technol Beijing, Sch Automat & Elect Engn, Beijing 100083, Peoples R China.	hewei.ac@gmail.com			National Natural Science Foundation of China [61522302, 61403063]; National Basic Research Program of China (973 Program) [2014CB744206]; Fundamental Research Funds for the China Central Universities of UESTC [ZYGX2013Z003, ZYGX2015J120]; Fundamental Research Funds for the China Central Universities of USTB [FRF-TP-15-005C1]	The authors thank the Editor-In-Chief, the Associate Editor and the anonymous reviewers for their constructive comments which helped improve the quality and presentation of this paper. This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China under grant nos. 61522302 and 61403063, the National Basic Research Program of China (973 Program) under grant no. 2014CB744206, the Fundamental Research Funds for the China Central Universities of UESTC under grant nos. ZYGX2013Z003 and ZYGX2015J120, and the Fundamental Research Funds for the China Central Universities of USTB under grant no. FRF-TP-15-005C1.		44	6	6	2	22	INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET	HERTFORD	MICHAEL FARADAY HOUSE SIX HILLS WAY STEVENAGE, HERTFORD SG1 2AY, ENGLAND	1751-8644	1751-8652		IET CONTROL THEORY A	IET Contr. Theory Appl.	NOV 21	2016	10	17					2271	2278		10.1049/iet-cta.2016.0009				8	Automation & Control Systems; Engineering, Electrical & Electronic; Instruments & Instrumentation	Automation & Control Systems; Engineering; Instruments & Instrumentation	EC4FL	WOS:000388081600013					2018-12-10	
