PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Bao, XJ; Guo, ZH		Lopez, MB; Hadid, A; Pietikainen, M		Bao, Xianjie; Guo, Zhenhua			Extracting Region of Interest for Palmprint by Convolutional Neural Networks	2016 SIXTH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE PROCESSING THEORY, TOOLS AND APPLICATIONS (IPTA)	International Conference on Image Processing Theory Tools and Applications		English	Proceedings Paper	6th International Conference on Image Processing Theory, Tools and Applications (IPTA)	DEC 12-15, 2016	Oulu, FINLAND	IEEE, Univ Oulu, Ctr Machine Vis & Signal Anal, Federat Finnish Learned Soc, European Assoc Signal Proc, IEEE Finland Sect		Palmprint recognition; Convolutional neural net; Region of interest; Keypoint detection	RECOGNITION; FEATURES	Palm ROI extraction is one of the most important processes in palmprint recognition. The core idea is to employ the valley points between the fingers to establish a coordinate system and then obtain the ROI of palmprints. However when extracting the keypoints, conventional methods have three problems: (i) they are so sensitive to parameters and background noise due to lack of joint optimization, (ii) accuracy of the location of keypoints is not good enough, (iii) extracting speed can be faster. To address the above problems, this paper presents a novel approach to extract palmprint ROI using convolutional neural net. First, we present a new CNN to identify the palmprint being a left or right hand. Then we propose a specific designed and optimized CNN to detect the keypoints. Finally we test our method using palmprint verification algorithm, competitive coding. Experimental results show that the proposed novel method is not only fast and efficient, but also robust for ROI extraction.	[Bao, Xianjie; Guo, Zhenhua] Tsinghua Univ, Grad Sch Shenzhen, Shenzhen, Peoples R China	Guo, ZH (reprint author), Tsinghua Univ, Grad Sch Shenzhen, Shenzhen, Peoples R China.	abaoccy@163.com; zhenhua.guo@sz.tsinghua.edu.cn						23	0	0	3	7	IEEE	NEW YORK	345 E 47TH ST, NEW YORK, NY 10017 USA	2154-512X		978-1-4673-8910-5	INT CONF IMAG PROC			2016														6	Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence; Imaging Science & Photographic Technology	Computer Science; Imaging Science & Photographic Technology	BG9QD	WOS:000393589800046					2018-12-10	
