PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
S	Meng, D; Cao, GT; Duan, Y; Zhu, MH; Tu, LP; Xu, JT; Xu, D		Tian, T; Jiang, Q; Liu, Y; Burrage, K; Song, J; Wang, Y; Hu, X; Morishita, S; Zhu, Q; Wang, G		Meng, Dan; Cao, Guitao; Duan, Ye; Zhu, Minghua; Tu, Liping; Xu, Jiatuo; Xu, Dong			A Deep Tongue Image Features Analysis Model for Medical Application	2016 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON BIOINFORMATICS AND BIOMEDICINE (BIBM)	IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine-BIBM		English	Proceedings Paper	IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (IEEE BIBM)	DEC 15-18, 2016	Shenzhen, PEOPLES R CHINA	IEEE, IEEE Comp Soc, Natl Sci Fdn, Harbin Inst Technol		Tongue image; feature analysis; deep model; weighted SVM	CLASSIFICATION; SCALE	With the improvement of people's living standards, there is no doubt that people are paying more and more attention to their health. However, shortage of medical resources is a critical global problem. As a result, an intelligent prognostics system has a great potential to play important roles in computer aided diagnosis. Numerous papers reported that tongue features have been closely related to a human's state. Among them, the majority of the existing tongue image analyses and classification methods are based on the low-level features, which may not provide a holistic view of the tongue. Inspired by a deep convolutional neural network (CNN), we propose a deep tongue image feature analysis system to extract unbiased features and reduce human labor for tongue diagnosis. With the unbalanced sample distribution, it is hard to form a balanced classification model based on feature representations obtained by existing low-level and high-level methods. Our proposed deep tongue image feature analysis model learns high-level features and provide more classification information during training time, which may result in higher accuracy when predicting testing samples. We tested the proposed system on a set of 267 gastritis patients, and a control group of 48 healthy volunteers (labeled according to Western medical practices). Test results show that the proposed deep tongue image feature analysis model can classify a given tongue image into healthy and diseased state with an average accuracy of 91.49%, which demonstrates the relationship between human body's state and its deep tongue image features.	[Meng, Dan; Cao, Guitao; Duan, Ye] East China Normal Univ, Sch Comp Sci & Software Engn, Shanghai 200062, Peoples R China; [Zhu, Minghua; Tu, Liping] Univ Missouri, Dept Comp Sci, Columbia, MO 65211 USA; [Xu, Jiatuo; Xu, Dong] Shanghai Univ TCM, Dept TCM Informat, Shanghai, Peoples R China; [Xu, Jiatuo; Xu, Dong] Shanghai Univ TCM, Ctr Technol, Shanghai, Peoples R China	Cao, GT (reprint author), East China Normal Univ, Sch Comp Sci & Software Engn, Shanghai 200062, Peoples R China.; Zhu, MH (reprint author), Univ Missouri, Dept Comp Sci, Columbia, MO 65211 USA.	gtcao@sei.ecnu.edu.cn; mhzhu@sei.ecnu.edu.cn			Natural Science Foundation of China [61375015]	This work was supported by Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 61375015).		20	0	0	0	2	IEEE COMPUTER SOC	LOS ALAMITOS	10662 LOS VAQUEROS CIRCLE, PO BOX 3014, LOS ALAMITOS, CA 90720-1264 USA	2156-1125	2156-1133	978-1-5090-1610-5	IEEE INT C BIOINFORM			2016							1918	1922						5	Computer Science, Interdisciplinary Applications; Medical Informatics	Computer Science; Medical Informatics	BG9GY	WOS:000393191700330					2018-12-10	
